>> GOOD AFTERNOON WELCOME TO THE APRIL 14TH 2026 REGULAR
MEETING OF THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
>> MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL?
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY
PRESENT SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER NOT PRESENT SUPERVISOR
SIR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD PRESENT SUPERVISOR MANDELSON PRESENT
MANDEL MEN PRESENT SUPERVISOR AMILCAR MELGAR PRESENT
SUPERVISOR SAUTER SADR PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHERYL SHERRELL
PRESENT SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON PRESENT AND SUPERVISOR
WONG WONG PRESENT. >> MR. PRESIDENT, YOU HAVE A
QUORUM. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
>> THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT
WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL HOMELAND OF THE ROMITA SALONI
WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PENINSULA. AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF
THIS LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE
ROMITA COLONY HAVE NEVER CEDED LOST NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR
RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS
WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL
TERRITORY. AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE
BENEFIT FROM LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELANDS.
WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS,
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE ROMITA ALONI COMMUNITY AND BY
AFFIRMING THEIR RIGHTS AS FIRST PEOPLES.
>> COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF
ALLEGIANCE? I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG
OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA AND TO THE REPUBLIC FOR WHICH
IT STANDS ONE NATION UNDER GOD INDIVISIBLE.
>> ON BEHALF OF OUR BOARD I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF
AT S.F. GOV TV TODAY. THAT IS ESPECIALLY KALEENA
MENDOZA. THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR
MEETINGS AND MAKE THE TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE
PUBLIC ONLINE. MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO OUR 2
P.M. SPECIAL ORDER. >> YES THE SPECIAL ORDER AT 2
P.M. IS THE APPEARANCE BY THE HONORABLE MAYOR DANIEL LURIE.
HERE TO DISCUSS THE ELIGIBLE TOPICS SUBMITTED FROM THE
DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR, THE MAYOR MAY ADDRESS THE BOARD
INITIALLY FOR UP TO FIVE MINUTES.
>> WELCOME MR. MAYOR. DO YOU HAVE ANY OPENING
REMARKS? I DO.
GOOD AFTERNOON, BOARD PRESIDENT ADELMAN AND MEMBERS OF THE
BOARD. IN THE COMING WEEKS MY OFFICE
WILL FINALIZE THE PROPOSED BUDGET AND PREPARE THE FORMAL
PACKAGE FOR THE BOARD'S CONSIDERATION.
THANKS TO THIS BOARD WITH THE LEADERSHIP OF PRESIDENT
RANDLEMAN CHAIR CHAN AND MEMBERS OF THE BUDGET
COMMITTEE, WE MADE HARD BUT RESPONSIBLE CHOICES LAST YEAR
TO PASS A BUDGET THAT PROTECTED CORE SERVICES.
WHAT TAKING ROUGHLY $300 MILLION OFF OF OUR LONG TERM
STRUCTURAL DEFICIT. >> BUT DESPITE THAT PROGRESS WE
MADE LAST YEAR FEDERAL AND STATE CUTS TO HEALTH CARE
AND SAFETY NET FUNDING HAVE SET US BACK AND OUR DEFICIT WILL
REACH $1 BILLION IN THE COMING YEARS IF WE DO NOT ACT FURTHER
. THE IMPACTS OF H.R. ONE ALONE
MAY EXCEED $300 MILLION ANNUALLY AND COULD FORCE TENS
OF THOUSANDS OF SAN FRANCISCANS OFF OF MEDI-CAL AND SNAP.
NOT ONLY THAT BUT THE PROPOSED FEDERAL BUDGET FOR THE NEXT
FISCAL YEAR WOULD ELIMINATE CONTINUUM OF CARE HOMELESSNESS
FUNDING WHICH PROVIDES SERVICES OR SUBSIDIES FOR OVER 2200
HOUSEHOLDS CITYWIDE. LAST YEAR WE TOOK SIGNIFICANT
STEPS AWAY FROM THE LONGTIME PRACTICE OF USING ONE TIME
FUNDS TO PAY FOR ONGOING COSTS .
THIS CITY HAS TO STOP SPENDING MORE MONEY THAN WE HAVE.
TEMPORARY FIXES MAY BUY TIME BUT TACKLING THE STRUCTURAL
DEFICIT IS THE BEST THING WE CAN DO TO SET UP OUR CITY FOR A
BROAD BASED DURABLE RECOVERY. THIS YEAR WE ARE CONTINUING
THAT WORK AND I LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING WITH EACH OF YOU TO
ENSURE WE DELIVER A BUDGET THAT IS RESPONSIBLE, THAT PROTECTS
CORE SERVICES AND THAT HELPS ACCELERATE OUR CITY'S RECOVERY
. THANK YOU, MAYOR LURIE.
MADAM CLERK, COULD YOU PLEASE CALL THE TOPIC FOR DISTRICT 11?
>> THE FIRST TOPIC SUBMITTED BY THE MEMBER REPRESENTING
DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR CHEN IS THE REVENUE PROJECTIONS
AND PROPOSED LAYOFFS TO CITY WORKERS.
SUPERVISOR CHEN YOU MAY ASK YOUR OPENING QUESTION.
>> THANK YOU. PRESS THE GENTLEMAN.
THANK YOU, MAYOR, FOR JOINING US.
SAN FRANCISCO PRIDES ITSELF ON BEING A WORLD CLASS CITY THAT
PROVIDES WORLD CLASS SERVICES THAT MEET THE NEEDS OF ALMOST
VULNERABLE POPULATIONS. >> WE ALSO TAKE IMMENSE PRIDE
IN THE FACT THAT WE UPHOLD SOME OF THE HIGHEST LABOR STANDARDS
IN THE COUNTRY. WE ARE EXPERIENCING EXIGENCE SO
CONCERNS BETWEEN OUR LOCAL BUDGET DEFICIT AND UNCERTAINTY
WITH FUNDING AT THE STATE AND FEDERAL LEVEL.
BUT WE'RE ALSO SEEING MOMENTUM IN A POSITIVE IN A POSITIVE
DIRECTION. >> WE'RE NOW PROJECTING A 30%
REDUCTION IN THE DEFICIT ALONG WITH A 120 MILLION SETTLEMENT
FROM AIRBNB. >> GIVEN THIS IMPROVED PHYSICAL
OUTLOOK AND THE POTENTIAL FOR UP TO THREE HUNDRED MILLIONS
IN NEW REVENUE FROM PROPERTY, WHY ARE YOU STILL PURSUING A
100 MILLION IN CUTS TO CITY WORKERS?
>> I APPRECIATE THE QUESTION SUPERVISOR.
>> LET ME BE CLEAR WE NEVER WANT ANYONE TO LOSE THEIR JOBS
. THERE IS NO DOUBT THAT THESE
DECISIONS ARE PAINFUL. CITY EMPLOYEES COME TO WORK
EVERY SINGLE DAY TO SERVE THE PUBLIC AND MAKE OUR CITY
BETTER. AND WHILE THE MARCH 5TH YEAR
UPDATE DOES CONTAIN SOME ENCOURAGING NEWS, WE ARE FAR
FROM OUT OF THE WOODS WITH THE WORK WE'VE BEEN DOING TOGETHER
TO CREATE THE CONDITIONS FOR OUR RECOVERY.
BUSINESSES OF ALL SIZES ARE COMING BACK TO SAN FRANCISCO.
PEOPLE ARE STARTING TO SHOP DOWNTOWN AGAIN AND TAX REVENUE
IS HIGHER THAN PROJECTED. BUT I WANT TO MAKE IT CLEAR ONE
MORE TIME. WE ARE NOT OUT OF THE WOODS.
OUR ECONOMIC RECOVERY IS STILL EXTREMELY FRAGILE.
WE STILL HAVE A FIVE YEAR STRUCTURAL DEFICIT THAT WILL
RISE TO $1 BILLION IF WE DO NOTHING ALONGSIDE POTENTIAL
ADDITIONAL FEDERAL AND STATE CUTS AS A RESULT OF THOSE CUTS.
WE MUST DEDICATE A SIGNIFICANT AMOUNT OF FUNDING TO PRESERVE
OUR SOCIAL SAFETY NET AND THE ONE TIME FUNDING RELEASED
THROUGH THAT SETTLEMENT THAT YOU REFERRED TO WILL HELP AVOID
DEEPER CUTS. AND WE PLAN TO SPREAD THAT
MONEY OUT OVER THREE YEARS SO WE DON'T CREATE A FISCAL CLIFF
BY SPENDING IT ALL AT ONCE. THE STEPS WE HAVE TAKEN LET ME
REITERATE ARE INCREDIBLY PAINFUL BUT THEY ARE NECESSARY
TO CONTINUE THE WORK WE HAVE BEEN DOING TO MANAGE TAXPAYER
DOLLARS RESPONSIBLY DELIVER THE BEST POSSIBLE SERVICES AND SET
UP OUR CITY FOR LONG FOR A LONG LASTING RECOVERY.
>> THANK YOU MAYOR LURIE SUPERVISOR CHEN YOU MAY NOW ASK
A FOLLOW UP QUESTION DIRECTLY RELATED TO THE OPENING QUESTION
. >> GREAT.
THANK YOU, MAYOR, FOR YOUR RESPONSE.
AND MY FOLLOW UP QUESTION IS THAT WHAT IS THE URGENCY TO
IMPLEMENT MID-YEAR CUTS LIKE LAY OFF NOW RATHER THAN
ALLOWING THE BOARD TO REVIEW THE UPDATED BUDGET AND CONSIDER
WHETHER CUTS OF THE SCALE ARE STILL NECESSARY?
>> AGAIN, LET ME BE CLEAR THERE'S NO DOUBT THAT THESE
DECISIONS ARE PAINFUL. THESE ARE CITY EMPLOYEES THAT
WORK HARD EVERY DAY TO MAKE OUR CITY BETTER.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME AS WE LOOK AT A BUDGET DEFICIT RISING TO
$1 BILLION WITH SIGNIFICANT FEDERAL AND STATE CUTS, WE HAVE
A CHOICE TAKE ACTION NOW OR BE FORCED TO DO TWICE AS MUCH
IN THE COMING YEARS. PROTECTING CORE SERVICES
CONTINUES TO BE AT THE CENTER OF OUR APPROACH TO THE BUDGET.
WE CANNOT CONTINUE TO SPREAD OURSELVES THIN BY DOING
EVERYTHING A LITTLE LESS WELL AS WE WORK TO BRING SPENDING
IN LINE WITH REVENUE. >> WE ARE RESETTING HOW CITY
GOVERNMENT WORKS SO WE CAN DELIVER BETTER, MORE
ACCOUNTABLE SERVICES AND ENSURE WE CAN PAY FOR THEM.
THIS IS A HARD BUDGET AND I'M NOT GOING TO PRETEND OTHERWISE.
BUT SAN FRANCISCO AND I DESERVE A GOVERNMENT THAT IS HONEST
ABOUT THE CHALLENGE DISCIPLINED ABOUT TAXPAYER DOLLARS
AND CLEAR ABOUT WHAT WE WILL PROTECT.
MY JOB IS TO CLOSE THE STRUCTURAL GAP RESPONSIBLY
PROTECTING THE ESSENTIALS AND PUT THIS CITY ON STRONGER
FOOTING FOR THE COMING YEARS SUPERVISOR.
AND I LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING WITH YOU AND THE REST OF YOUR
COLLEAGUES TO BALANCE THIS BUDGET WHILE PROTECTING OUR
CORE SERVICES. >> THANK YOU MAYOR LURIE.
YOU MAY NOW ASK A QUESTION TO SUPERVISOR CHEN OR TO ANY OTHER
SUPERVISOR IN ATTENDANCE PERTAINING TO THE SAME TOPIC
BUT NOT NECESSARILY RELATED TO THE PREVIOUS QUESTION.
>> THANK YOU. I'M GOOD.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH. >> SUPERVISOR THREE THANK YOU
FOR ALL RIGHT. THESE MATTERS HAVE BEEN
DISCUSSED AND WILL BE FILED AFTER GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
MADAM CLERK LET'S GO BACK TO OUR COMMUNICATIONS.
>> THANK YOU MR. PRESIDENT. THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
WELCOMES ALL OF YOUR ATTENDANCE HERE IN THE BOARD'S LEGISLATIVE
CHAMBER ROOM 250 IN THE SECOND FLOOR IN CITY HALL.
AND WHEN YOU'RE NOT ABLE TO BE HERE, YOU CAN WATCH THE
PROCEEDING ON SMG OVID.TV OR CHANNEL 26 OR VIEW THE LIVE
STREAM AT W W W DOT AS OF G OF ETV.ORG.
IF YOU HAVE PUBLIC COMMENT THAT YOU WOULD LIKE TO SUBMIT
IN WRITING YOU CAN SEND AN EMAIL TO BOSS AT S.F. GOV.ORG
OR USE THE POSTAL SERVICE. >> JUST ADDRESS THE ENVELOPE
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS THE NUMBER ONE DR.
CARLTON BE GOOD PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244 SAN FRANCISCO
CALIFORNIA 94102 IF YOU NEED TO MAKE A REASONABLE ACCOMMODATION
FOR A FUTURE MEETING UNDER THE AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT
OR TO REQUEST LANGUAGE ASSISTANCE, PLEASE CONTACT THE
CLERK'S OFFICE AT LEAST TWO BUSINESS OFFICE DAYS IN ADVANCE
BY CALLING (415) 554-5184. AND FINALLY, AS I STATED LAST
WEEK PURSUANT TO A MEMO DATED APRIL 7TH, 2026 FROM SUPERVISOR
JACKIE FIELDER, A MOTION WE WOULD NEED TO RENEW A MOTION
EACH WEEK BETWEEN APRIL 7TH AND JUNE 30TH 2026 AS SHE HAS
REQUESTED TO BE EXCUSED FROM TODAY'S MEETING.
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO EXCUSE SUPERVISOR FIELDER FROM TODAY'S
MEETING MOVED BY MAHMOOD SECONDED BY CHAN.
COLLEAGUES, I THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT WITHOUT OBJECTION.
WITHOUT OBJECTION. >> SUPERVISOR FIELDER IS
EXCUSED. AND MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO
APPROVAL OF OUR MEETING MINUTES.
>> YES. APPROVAL OF THE MARCH 10TH 2026
BOARD MEETING MINUTES. >> CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO
APPROVE THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED MOVED BY CHERYL
SECONDED BY CHAN MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON
THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I
SUPERVISOR SADR SADR EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EYES
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
AND SUPERVISOR MANDEL MEN HIGH MEN AND WOMEN EITHER ATTORNEYS
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MINUTES WILL BE APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC
COMMENT AS PRESENTED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO NOW TO OUR
CONSENT AGENDA PLEASE CALL ITEMS TWO THROUGH SEVEN
TOGETHER ITEMS TWO THROUGH SEVEN ARE ON CONSENT.
>> THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED TO BE ROUTINE IF A MEMBER
OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED SEPARATELY.
>> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS TWO THROUGH SEVEN
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I AND SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI
MANDOLIN I THEIR ATTORNEYS WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE
ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO
UNFINISHED BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER EIGHT ITEM EIGHT
THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE OFFICE OF THE
ASSESSOR RECORDER TO EXECUTE THE SECOND AMENDMENT TO A
CONTRACT WITH SAPIENT CORPORATION FOR THE
IMPLEMENTATION AND MAINTENANCE OF THE PROPERTY ASSESSMENT
SYSTEM REPLACEMENT PROJECT TO INCREASE THE CONTRACT BY 6.7
MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL AMOUNT OF 33.9 MILLION AND TO EXTEND
THE CONTRACT DURATION FROM NINE YEARS AND TWO MONTHS TO 13
YEARS AND EIGHT MONTHS FOR A TOTAL TERM NOVEMBER 1ST 2018
THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2032 SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU
COLLEAGUES FOR YOUR VOTE TO ALLOW IT CONTINUANCE I BELIEVE
NOW WE HAVE THOSE INFORMATION ON FILE ON FOR THIS CONTRACT
AMENDMENT SO THANK YOU AND I WILL BE VOTING IN SUPPORT
TODAY. >> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU CHAIR CHAN OR WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME
CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
NUMBER NINE ITEM NINE ORDINANCE TO APPROVE THE AIRPORT
SURVEILLANCE TECHNOLOGY POLICY GOVERNING THE USE OF THE
TRANSPORTATION NETWORK COMPANY VIRTUAL QUEUE TECHNOLOGY
COLLEAGUES THIS ITEM IS ON ITS SECOND READING BUT WE DID
RECEIVE A LETTER YESTERDAY FROM LYFT ASKING FOR TIME TO TALK
WITH THE AIRPORT ABOUT THIS ORDINANCE AND THE POLICY.
THEY ASKED FOR A FOUR WEEK CONTINUANCE.
I CALLED THE EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF THE AIRPORT OR THE DIRECTOR
OF THE AIRPORT TO GET HIS PERSPECTIVE AND SEE WHETHER IT
WOULD MAKE SENSE TO CONTINUE THIS A WEEK FOR THEM TO MAYBE
HAVE CONVERSATIONS AND ADDRESS WHATEVER CONCERNS LYFT MAY
HAVE. HE SAID HE THOUGHT THAT SOUNDED
REASONABLE. I WOULD LIKE TO DO THAT.
CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO CONTINUE THIS ITEM ONE WEEK MOVED BY
CHERYL IS THAT A SECOND OR A QUESTION MOVED BY CHERYL?
IS THERE A SECOND SECONDED BY CHEN SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK
YOU. >> PRESIDENT MADE AN AMENDMENT
SO WE ARE HONORING A REQUEST BY ONE SINGLE COMPANY THAT HAS AN
ISSUE IF THE BOARD CONTINUES THIS FOR ONE WEEK WE ARE GIVING
THEM ONE OF THE FOUR WEEKS THAT THEY'VE ASKED TO HAVE THIS
CONTINUED LIFT IS A STAKEHOLDER IN THIS POLICY AND THAT I THINK
THEY'RE CONCERNED ABOUT OR THEIR THEIR QUESTIONS ARE ABOUT
HOW THE SURVEILLANCE POLICY WILL IMPACT LYFT AND LYFT
DRIVERS WHO ARE GOING TO THE AIRPORT.
>> IT'S IT'S YEAH SO I DON'T KNOW MORE THAN THAT AND AGAIN I
ONLY KNOW WE'RE MORE CONCERNED ABOUT LYFT DRIVERS THAN THE
GENERAL PUBLIC THE GENERAL POPULATION LIKE WE'RE GOING TO
DO THIS FOR ONE. >> I MEAN YOU'RE PROPOSING TO
CONTINUE THIS FOR ONE COMPANY I'M PROPOSING I AM PROPOSING A
ONE WEEK CONTINUANCE TO ALLOW THE AIRPORT TO COMMUNICATE WITH
ONE OF ITS STAKEHOLDERS THAT APPEARS TO HAVE A CONCERN ABOUT
THIS POLICY. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL THE
ROLL ON ITEM NINE SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR
SAUTER SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON NO SUPERVISOR WANG WANG EYES SUPERVISOR CHEN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I AND SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI
MANAGEMENT I THERE ARE NINE EYES AND ONE NO ALL RIGHT WITH
SUPERVISOR WALTON VOTING NO SO THE MOTION PASSES AND WE WILL
SEE THIS ITEM IN A WEEK. >> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
NUMBER TEN. ITEM TEN THIS IS AN ORDINANCE
TO AMEND THE ENVIRONMENT CODE TO UPDATE THE CITY'S CLIMATE
ACTION GOALS AND PLANNING PROCESS AND TO UPDATE CITY
DEPARTMENTS ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES PERTAINING
TO THE CITY'S CLIMATE ACTION GOALS AND TO AFFIRM THE SECOND
DETERMINATION PLEASE CALL THE ROLL SUPERVISOR.
>> MELGAR HAS A QUESTION. >> OH SORRY.
I JUST WANTED TO MAKE SURE THOUGH THAT IT AS A CO-SPONSOR
I THOUGHT I DID THAT AT COMMITTEE BUT IT WAS A
COMMITTEE REPORT SO MAYBE IT DIDN'T STICK.
THANK YOU SO MUCH. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR.
ON ITEM TEN SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR
EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EYES SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I AND SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI
MANDELL MIN I THERE ARE TEN EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 11
ITEM 11 RESOLUTION TO RETROACTIVELY AUTHORIZE THE
OFFICE OF THE CITY ATTORNEY TO ACCEPT AND EXPEND A $600,000
GRANT FROM THE CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF INDUSTRIAL
RELATIONS LABOR COMMISSIONER'S OFFICE FOR THE WORKERS RIGHTS
ENFORCEMENT GRANT PROGRAM TO FUND THE ENFORCEMENT OF STATE
LABOR LAWS AUGUST 1ST, 2025 THROUGH JULY 31ST, 2026 AND I
THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 12 .
>> ITEM 12 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE AND AUTHORIZE THE
GENERAL MANAGER OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES
COMMISSION ON BEHALF OF CLEAN POWER IF TO PARTICIPATE
IN CALIFORNIA COMMUNITY POWERS PROCUREMENT OF THE WILLOW ROCK
LONG DURATION STORAGE PROJECT BY ENTERING INTO THE BUYER
LIABILITY PASS THROUGH AGREEMENT AND THE PARTICIPATION
SHARE AGREEMENT FOR A TOTAL AMOUNT OF 75.9 MILLION AND A
CONTRACT DURATION OF 20 YEARS ESTIMATED TO BEGIN BY JULY 1ST,
2030 AND THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2050 .
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM 13. ITEM 13 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO
APPROVE THE FIRST MODIFICATION TO A PROFESSIONAL SERVICES
AGREEMENT FOR AIRPORT CONTRACT NUMBER 50359 FOR GENERAL
AIRPORT SECURITY SERVICES BETWEEN COVENANT AVIATION
SECURITY LLC AND THE CITY AND COUNTY TO INCREASE THE
CONTRACT AMOUNT BY 10.5 MILLION FOR A NEW AMOUNT OF 20.3
MILLION AND A TWO YEAR CONTRACT TERM EXTENSION NOW THROUGH JUNE
30TH 2028 WITH ONE REMAINING OPTION TO EXTEND FOR AN
ADDITIONAL TWO YEARS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAME CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 14.
ITEM 14 RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE DEPARTMENT OF TECHNOLOGY TO
ENTER INTO THE THIRD AMENDMENT TO THE AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE
CITY AND COUNTY AND METHINKS LLC FOR THE PURCHASE OF ORACLE
PRODUCTS AND CLOUD COMPUTING SOLUTIONS TO INCREASE THE
AGREEMENT BY APPROXIMATELY 34.5 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL AMOUNT
OF 94.5 MILLION AND A 31 MONTH TERM EXTENSION NOW MAY 1ST 2021
THROUGH NOVEMBER 30TH 2028. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 15.
>> ITEM 15 RESOLUTION TO RETROACTIVELY AUTHORIZE THE
DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH TO ACCEPT AND EXPEND A AN
APPROXIMATE $7.9 MILLION GRANT FROM THE CALIFORNIA BOARD OF
STATE AND COMMUNITY CORRECTIONS TO PARTICIPATE IN THE PROGRAM
ENTITLED PROPOSITION 47 COHORT FIVE TERM OF OCTOBER 1ST 2025
THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2029 AND TO APPROVE THE NOTICE OF AWARD
AGREEMENT PURSUANT TO THE CHARTER SECTION 9.118 SUB A
SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL IT A
NUMBER 16 ITEM 16 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO RETROACTIVELY
AUTHORIZE THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC DEFENDER'S OFFICE TO
ACCEPT AND EXPEND AN APPROXIMATE $850,000 GRANT FROM
THE OFFICE OF THE STATE PUBLIC DEFENDER TO MAINTAIN THE
CAPACITY OF THE OFFICES POST CONVICTION UNIT ALSO KNOWN AS
THE FREEDOM PROJECT TO MEET THE INCREASED DEMAND FOR
DECARCERATION REENTRY AND RE SENTENCING REFORMS SERVICES
FEBRUARY 1ST, 2026 THROUGH JUNE 1ST, 2028 AND I THINK WE CAN
TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
17 ITEM 17 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE AND AUTHORIZE THE
MAYOR'S OFFICE OF HOUSING AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT TO
JOINTLY APPLY WITH 629 POST LLC AND SWORDS TO PLOWSHARES THE
VETERANS RIGHTS ORGANIZATION TO THE CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF
HOUSING AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT FOR THE HOMEKEY
PLUS GRANT FOR THE PROPERTY LOCATED AT 629 POST STREET IN A
TOTAL AMOUNT OF 15.9 MILLION OR THE MAXIMUM AWARD AMOUNT
ALLOWABLE UNDER THE NOTICE OF FUNDING AVAILABILITY WHICHEVER
IS GREATER ON BEHALF OF THE CITY AND COUNTY SAY HOUSE SAME
CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. >> PLEASE CALL ITEMS 18 THROUGH
31 TOGETHER ITEMS 18 THROUGH 31 ARE 14 ORDINANCES THAT AMEND
THE PLANNING CODE TO DESIGNATE VARIOUS PROPERTY AS LANDMARKS
CONSISTING WITH THE STANDARDS SET FORTH IN ARTICLE TEN OF THE
PLANNING CODE ITEM 18 THIS IS FOR THE BARBARA'S HOUSE LOCATED
AT 40 220TH STREET. ITEM 19 IS THESE ARE ZAHAV
LOCATED AT 220 DANVERS STREET. ITEM 20 IS THE AMERICAN INDIAN
HISTORICAL SOCIETY TO TAQWA HOUSE LOCATED AT 1451 MASONIC
AVENUE. ITEM 21 IS FOR THE BANK OF
ITALY BRANCH BUILDING LOCATED AT 400 THROUGH 410 CASTRO
STREET. ITEM 22 CASTRO ROCK STREAM
STEAM BATHS LOCATED AT 578 THROUGH 582 CASTRO STREET.
ITEM 23 IS FOR ENGINE COMPANY NUMBER 13 LOCATED AT 1458
VALENCIA STREET. ITEM 24 IS FOR THE HOSE COMPANY
NUMBER 30 FIREHOUSE LOCATED AT 1757 WALLER STREET.
ITEM 25 IS FOR THE FULL MOON COFFEEHOUSE LOCATED AT 4416
18TH STREET. ITEM 26 IS FOR THE GOLFERS ON
GUERRERO LOCATED AT 102 GUERRERO STREET.
ITEM 27 IS FOR MODS LOCATED AT 929 THROUGH 941 COLE STREET.
ITEM 28 IS FOR THE MISSION FOLK VICTORIAN HOME LOCATED AT 361
SAN JOSE AVENUE. ITEM 29 IS FOR THE SAN
FRANCISCO AIDS FOUNDATION BUILDING LOCATED AT 514 THROUGH
520 CASTRO STREET. ITEM 30 IS FOR ST MATTHEW'S
CHURCH LOCATED AT 3280 1/16 STREET.
ITEM 31 IS FOR SAINT NICHOLAS CATHEDRAL LOCATED AT 25 15TH
STREET AND FOR ALL ITEMS TO AFFIRM THE SECRET DETERMINATION
AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> COLLEAGUES LET'S TAKE THESE ITEMS SAME HOUSE SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCES ARE PASSED ON FIRST
READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 32.
>> ITEM 32 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO ADD THE COMMEMORATIVE STREET
NAME OFFICER LIEU AND TANKEL WAY TO THE 300 BLOCK OF EDDY
STREET IN RECOGNITION OF SAN FRANCISCO POLICE OFFICER ILIA
LOU ENTANGLES COURAGE AND DEDICATION TO THE PEOPLE OF
THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM 33. >> ITEM 33 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE
TO AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO ESTABLISH THE FIRE CODE
TECHNICAL ADVISORY COUNCIL TO EVALUATE AND ADVISE THE BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS, THE MAYOR AND THE FIRE DEPARTMENT ON THE
CRITERIA AND TYPES OF EVIDENCE THE FIRE MARSHAL SHOULD
CONSIDER IN DETERMINING WHETHER TO WAIVE, MODIFY OR DELAY
CERTAIN COMPLIANCE REQUIREMENTS UNDER THE FIRE CODE THAT
CERTAIN EXISTING HIGH RISE RESIDENTIAL BUILDINGS HAVE
SPRINKLER SYSTEMS AND TO SET FORTH THE MEMBERSHIP AND DUTIES
OF THE FIRE CODE TECHNICAL ADVISORY COUNCIL.
>> CHAIR WALTON THANK YOU SO MUCH.
PRESIDENT MELAMINE. COLLEAGUES, I JUST WANTED TO
STATE MY OBJECTIONS IN PUBLIC FOR THE RECORD I DIDN'T MAKE IT
CLEAR IN COMMITTEE THAT MY MAIN CONCERN IS I THINK IT'S TOTALLY
INAPPROPRIATE FOR A SUPERVISOR TO SERVE ON AN AUXILIARY
COMMITTEE THAT IS SET UP FOR COMMUNITY.
I THINK IT SETS A BAD PRECEDENT AND UNDER HAS THE UNDERTONES OF
POSSIBLE COERCION DUE TO THE FACT THAT THIS COMMITTEE GIVES
RECOMMENDATIONS TO THE FIRE COMMISSIONER.
AS WE KNOW, SUPERVISORS SHOULD NOT BE DIRECTING DEPARTMENT
STAFF AND WE ALREADY HAVE AN OVERSIGHT ROLE AFTER
RECOMMENDATIONS ARE MADE. IN ADDITION, SUPERVISORS ON
THESE COMMITTEES CAN UNDERMINE THE VOICES OF THE PEOPLE WE
REPRESENT. I CAN UNDERSTAND THE
SUPERVISORY APPOINTMENT POSSIBLY BUT NOT AN ACTUAL
SUPERVISOR SERVING AND MAKING RECOMMENDATIONS I BELIEVE IS
INAPPROPRIATE AND A POSSIBLE CONFLICT OF INTEREST
AND THEREFORE I WILL BE VOTING NO.
>> SUPERVISOR MELGAR. >> I JUST HAVE A QUESTION OF
CLARIFICATION SINCE YOU'RE THE RULES COMMITTEE CHAIR AND YOU
KNOW I DIFFERENT. >> SO DO YOU HAVE AN AMENDMENT
TO THIS LEGISLATION OR ANYTHING THAT YOU'RE PROPOSING OR YOU'RE
JUST. >> I DIDN'T PROPOSE ANY
AMENDMENTS AND IT WAS CLEAR THAT MY COLLEAGUES ON THE RULES
COMMITTEE ARE OKAY WITH THIS. SO I DIDN'T FEEL THAT IT WOULD
MAKE ANY SENSE TO PROPOSE AN AMENDMENT THAT WOULD GET SHUT
DOWN. >> OKAY.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM 33.
>> SUPERVISOR MELGAR I MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SAUTER HER EYES
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON NO
SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EYES SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I AND SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN
MANAGEMENT I THERE ARE TEN EYES AND ONE NO WITH SUPERVISOR
PARDON ME THERE ARE NINE EYES AND ONE NO WITH SUPERVISOR
WALTON VOTING NO AND THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST
READING MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR 2:30 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER
RECOGNITION OF COMMENDATIONS. >> OH YES.
THIS IS THE RECOGNITION OF COMMENDATIONS FOR MERITORIOUS
SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND TODAY WE
ARE STARTING WITH DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR CHEN.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU BOTH FOR PRESENT.
>> MAY I HAVE OUR COMMANDER OUR HURRY TO BE AT THE PODIUM?
>> THANK YOU. >> COLLEAGUES, I'M SO PROUD TO
HONOR AMY HERR TODAY COMMANDER OF THE GOLDEN GATE DIVISION WHO
HAS SPENT HER LIFE AND CAREER FINALLY KEEPING OUR COMMUNITIES
SAFE AND ADVOCATING FOR A MORE DIVERSE POLICE FORCE.
AMY HAS HAD A VAST CAREER WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
DEPARTMENT SERVING AS TWO PATROL OFFICERS IN THE
TENDERLOIN, RICHMOND AND INGLESIDE AS A SURGEON
AND TO CENTRAL AND SOUTHERN STATION ENSURING PUBLIC SAFETY
ON MUNI AS CAPTAIN AFTER INGLESIDE STATION FOR WHICH I
WANT TO EXPRESS MY DEEP DEEP GRATITUDE.
AND MORE NOW AS A COMMANDER OF THE GOLDEN GATE DIVISION SHE
CONTINUES TO LEAD WITH EXCELLENCE AND CENTERING WHAT
EQUITY RESILIENCE AND DETERMINATION DEFINE AMY.
AND HER COMMITMENT EXTENDS FAR BEYOND PUBLIC SAFETY.
>> AMY IS A TIRELESS ADVOCATE AND MENTOR PAVING THE WAY FOR
FUTURE GENERATIONS OF WOMEN SERVING THE FORCE, BREAKING
BARRIERS AND AND PROVIDING THAT WOMAN BELONG IN LEADERSHIP
AND IN PUBLIC SERVICE. SHE UNDERSTANDS DEEPLY THAT
WHEN OUR FORCES ARE PRESENT, WHEN OUR FORCES ARE REPRESENTED
AFTER SARI, SHE UNDERSTANDS DEEPLY THAT WHEN OUR FORCES ARE
REPRESENTATIVE, OFF AND RESPONSIVE TO OUR CITY'S
DIVERSE COMMUNITY WE ARE SAFER. >> BUT IT'S NOT JUST HER ETHIC
THAT MAKES HER SUCH A STRONG LEADER.
>> IT'S ALSO HER WARM INTELLIGENCE AND OPENNESS TO
THE WORKING WITH OTHERS AND HAVE CONTRIBUTED TO HOW
BELOVED SHE IS BY THE BOARD OF BY THE BORDER AND ALSO IN THE
COMMUNITY. SHE IT'S A PERFECT EXAMPLE OF
HOW WOMEN CAN BE KIND AND COMPASSIONATE BUT ALSO
FEISTY AND STRONG WITHOUT COMPROMISING VALUES OR QUALITY
OF WATER. >> COMMANDER HERING WE CONTINUE
TO BE INSPIRED BY YOUR LEADERSHIP, YOUR WORK TO SHAPE
A SAFER, MORE INCLUSIVE AND A THRIVING FUTURE FOR SAN
FRANCISCO. >> THANK YOU FOR ALL THAT YOU
HAVE DONE. AND I KNOW THAT I'M NOW LONG
IN SAYING THAT I'M VERY EXCITED TO SEE WHAT YOU DO IN THE NEXT
CHAPTER. >> THANK YOU.
AND I BEFORE YOU SPEAK WE HAVE MORE.
YEAH, THERE'S A LAW THERE'S A LONG LINE OF PEOPLE WHO WANT TO
SAY NICE THINGS ABOUT YOU, COMMANDER.
THE SUPERVISOR MELGAR THANK YOU, PRESIDENT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR TEN FOR THIS
WONDERFUL COMMENDATION. >> COMMAND HER HER WORDS PUT
HER IN COMMANDER I AM SO HONORED TO HAVE WORKED WITH YOU
ALL THESE YEARS. YOU ARE.
I'M ONE OF YOUR BIGGEST FANS. YOU ARE BY FAR SOMEBODY THAT I
HAVE SEEN WHOSE WORK I'VE LONG ADMIRED YOUR ADVOCACY FOR WOMEN
IN THE DEPARTMENT HAS MADE AN ENORMOUS DIFFERENCE FOR
RECRUITMENT AND FOR ADVANCEMENT FOR FOLKS SEEING THEMSELVES
IN THE FUTURE OF THEIR PROFESSION OR LIVES WITHIN OUR
DEPARTMENT. AND I AM DEEPLY GRATEFUL FOR
EVERYTHING YOU WERE DONE FOR YOUR VISIBILITY, FOR YOUR FEAR
FIERCENESS BUT ALSO THE GRACE WITH WHICH YOU YOU KNOW,
ENTERED THESE CONVERSATIONS WHICH ARE NOT EASY.
SO I'M GRATEFUL FOR THAT AND FOLKS MAY NOT KNOW THAT
DISTRICT SEVEN IS ALSO HOME TO SEVERAL JEWISH COMMUNITY
ORGANIZATIONS. AND COMMANDER HURWITZ HAS ALSO
BEEN OUR LIAISON THROUGH SOME OF THE TOUGHEST TIMES IN THE
COMMUNITY'S HISTORY HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
AND FOR THAT AGAIN FOR YOUR KINDNESS, YOUR EMPATHY, YOUR
GRACE, YOUR STRATEGY AND YOUR INTELLIGENCE, YOUR OUTSTANDING
COMMUNICATION SKILLS AND ALL NAVIGATING ALL THAT ALSO I AM
DEEPLY GRATEFUL. AND FINALLY I AM GRATEFUL FOR
YOUR COMMUNICATION SKILLS BECAUSE YOU ARE SOMEONE WHO
ALWAYS KNOWS WHAT TO SAY AND WHEN TO SAY IT, HOW TO SAY
IT IN A WAY THAT GETS HEARD. THAT'S RESPECT ARTFUL BUT ALSO
CLEAR AND AND ON POINT. SO I AM SO GLAD THAT YOU ARE
WHERE YOU ARE. I'M GRATEFUL THAT YOU HAVE BEEN
WILLING TO STEP UP IN LEADERSHIP AT BEING AS
WONDERFUL AND AWESOME AS YOU ARE BECAUSE YOU ARE A SHINING
EXAMPLE OF LEADERSHIP OF FEMALE FIERCE FEMALE LEADERSHIP WITHIN
THE DEPARTMENT AND YOU ARE PAVING THE WAY FOR OTHERS SO
THANK YOU FOR THE COMMENDATION. SUPERVISOR CHEN AND I'M SO GLAD
WE'RE DOING THIS. >> SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU
PRESIDENT MAN OF MAN AND THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHEN FOR
HONORING COMMANDER HURWITZ. I JUST WANT TO SAY
CONGRATULATIONS. I THINK THIS IS WELL-DESERVED
AND OBVIOUSLY WE MISS YOU AT THE INGLESIDE STATION BUT I'M
GLAD THAT YOU HAVE GONE ON TO PLAY A ROLE THAT PROVIDES A LOT
OF HOPE AND OPPORTUNITY FOR OTHER WOMEN AND OTHER PEOPLE
IN THE DEPARTMENT AND REALLY JUST HAVE BEEN AN EXAMPLE OF
WHAT LEADERSHIP LOOKS LIKE. SO THANK YOU SO MUCH AND I
APPRECIATE THE TIME AND OPPORTUNITIES THAT WE'VE
HAD TO WORK TOGETHER. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN AND I AM A
BIG FAN OF COMMANDER HURWITZ AS WELL.
I JUST APPRECIATE EVERYTHING THAT YOU HAVE DONE WHILE YOUR
YOU WERE CAPTAIN AT SOUTHERN AND JUST TO SAY HOW MUCH IT
MEANS TO ME AS SOMEONE WHO WAS A COLLEAGUE AT THE SAN
FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT IN A CIVILIAN CAPACITY BUT
SOMEBODY WHO WAS ALSO FROM THE LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY I HAVE
REALLY BEEN PROUD OF SAN FRANCISCO'S HISTORY OF LGBT
PLUS LEADERSHIP IN OUR POLICE DEPARTMENT.
GOING BACK ONE OF MY FIRST MENTORS WAS WAYNE FRIDAY WHEN
HE SERVED ON THE POLICE COMMISSION AND I WAS JUST
ALWAYS PROUD OF OUR CITY AND BEING AS INCLUSIVE AS IT
WAS WHEN LAW ENFORCEMENT REALLY WASN'T AS WELCOMING.
SO THAT JUST MEANS THE WORLD TO ME.
I AM GRATEFUL TO SEE YOU THAT YOU'RE GETTING PROMOTE
PROMOTED. I'M A LITTLE DISAPPOINTED
BECAUSE OBVIOUSLY I DON'T REPRESENT A DISTRICT THAT IS
COVERED BY THE GOLDEN GATE DISTRICT.
I'M IN THE METRO DISTRICT BUT THAT WILL NOT STOP ME FROM
CALLING WHEN I WHEN I NEED HELP.
SO I JUST APPRECIATE EVERYTHING THAT YOU HAVE DONE FOR OUR CITY
AND FOR THE POLICE DEPARTMENT AND I'LL GO LAST BEFORE YOU GET
TO BE COMMANDER. I JUST WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR
CHEN FOR DOING THIS. I AM ALSO A LITTLE BUMMED THAT
I DON'T GET TO CONTINUE TO ENJOY WORKING WITH YOU AS A AS
A CAPTAIN AT INGLESIDE WHERE I GOT TO KNOW YOU BUT I AM HAPPY
TO SEE YOU RISING UP THROUGH THE RANKS.
REPRESENTATION MATTERS OUR POLICE DEPARTMENT GETS BETTER
AS IT INCLUDES MORE AND MORE PEOPLE WHO REFLECT THE
DIVERSITY OF SAN FRANCISCO. AS A JEW I LIKE HAVING A JEW
IN LEADERSHIP IN THE DEPARTMENT AND I LIKE HAVING SOMEONE I CAN
CALL WHEN THE JEWISH COMMUNITY HAS A NEED OR THE COMMUNITY
HAS A NEED AND I'VE BEEN ABLE TO DO THAT WITH YOU ON A NUMBER
OF OCCASIONS. SO THANK YOU FOR BEING THERE
AND KEEP DOING IT. AND NOW IT'S YOUR TURN.
>> I GOT THANK YOU. I AM TRULY HUMBLED AND IF YOU
KNOW ME YOU KNOW THAT TAKES A LOT SO THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> YOU KNOW WHEN YOU FIRST TOLD ME ABOUT THIS IDEA I WAS LIKE
OKAY, LIKE FOR WHAT? BECAUSE TO ME I SHOW UP AND I
DO MY JOB AND I CARE FOR PEOPLE AND I, I REALLY DON'T NEED
RECOGNITION OR AN AWARD FOR IT BECAUSE I LOVE IT AND IT THIS
REALLY MEANS THE WORLD TO ME THAT I GET TO BE HERE AND SHARE
THIS AND I HAVE THE CHIEF, THE COMMAND STAFF AND MY MY
OUTSTANDING CAPTAIN FROM PARK STATION AND THE HONDA'S
AND THEY'RE ALL HERE YOU GUYS WANT TO STAND UP AND TAKE A BOW
BECAUSE WE ALL DO IT. SO YOU KNOW, IT WAS GREAT WHEN
I WHEN I TOLD THEM LIKE 15 MINUTES AGO HEY, CAN YOU GUYS
COME DOWN AND AND HELP ME WITH SOMETHING BECAUSE I WAS AFRAID
I WAS GOING TO HAVE THE PARTY WHERE NOBODY SHOWED UP.
BUT THAT'S NOT THE CASE. SO YOU KNOW, I LOVE THE CITY.
I LOVE THE PEOPLE IN THIS ROOM .
YOU GUYS ARE FANTASTIC. YOU'RE DOING A TREMENDOUS JOB.
MR. PRESIDENT. >> SUPERVISORS I MEAN THANK YOU
SO MUCH. SO I'M GOING TO GO OVER THERE
NOW. THANK YOU.
OH, SORRY. THERE'S WORD I'M TRYING TO GET
OUT OF THIS STATE. >> OH, I YOU KNOW, PICTURE.
>> ALL RIGHT. NEXT UP FROM DISTRICT THREE
SUPERVISOR SAUTER THANK YOU, PRESIDENT MAN.
>> WOMAN COLLEAGUES TODAY I'M HONORED TO WELCOME NORTH BEACH
CITIZENS TO THE CHAMBERS. WE HAVE THEIR IRREPLACEABLE
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR KRISTI FAIRCHILD AND STAFF.
>> WOULD YOU ALL PLEASE COME ON UP AND JOIN US?
IT IS GOOD TO HAVE YOU HERE AS WE CELEBRATE YOUR 25 YEARS OF
EXTRAORDINARY SERVICE TO NORTH BEACH AND DISTRICT THREE IN ALL
OF SAN FRANCISCO. FOR THOSE WHO DON'T KNOW, FOR
ALMOST THREE DECADES NORTH BEACH CITIZENS HAS BEEN MAKING
SAN FRANCISCO BETTER ONE CITIZEN AT A TIME.
>> THEY OPERATE THE ONLY DROP IN CENTER FOR UNHOUSED
INDIVIDUALS IN THE NORTHEAST CORNER OF OUR CITY.
THEY COORDINATE A WEEKLY FOOD PANTRY, ORGANIZE NEIGHBORHOOD
BEAUTIFICATION TEAMS TO ALLOW FOR WORKFORCE OPPORTUNITIES
AND THEY WORK HAND IN HAND WITH UNHOUSED INDIVIDUALS.
NORTH BEACH CITIZENS WAS ESTABLISHED IN 2001 AND ITS
FORMATION WAS SUPPORTED BY NORTH BEACH RESIDENT
AND ACCLAIMED FILMMAKER FRANCIS FORD COPPOLA AND I KNOW THAT HE
WAS IN THE BUILDING EARLIER SO I WANT TO RECOGNIZE THAT I WANT
TO RECOGNIZE HIS CONTRIBUTION AND THAT IN THE MIDST OF A
STORIED CAREER HE TOOK THE TIME TO INVEST IN SAN FRANCISCO.
HIS IMPRINT HIS ECHOES CAN BE FELT IN EVERY CORNER OF
DISTRICT THREE. >> IF YOU'RE A FILM BUFF THAT
MIGHT BE UNION SQUARE AS THE SETTING OF THE CONVERSATION.
IF YOU LIKE COFFEE LIKE ME IT'S CERTAINLY A CAFE TRYST THE
FIRST ESPRESSO HOUSE IN THE WEST COAST WHERE YOU CAN ENJOY
A CAPPUCCINO IN THE SAME CORNER BOOTH WHERE THE GODFATHER IS
WRITTEN OR IF YOU LIKE ARCHITECTURE AND HISTORY THE
SENTINEL BUILDING MORE COMMONLY NOW KNOWN AS THE COPPOLA
BUILDING THAT HOUSES HIS STUDIOS NORTH BEACH CITIZENS
IMPACT IS ASTOUNDING OVER 630 INDIVIDUALS RECEIVED SERVICES
LAST YEAR. OVER 90% OF THE HOUSED CLIENTS
REMAIN STABLE THE HOUSE TODAY AND THEIR CARE REACHES THOSE
WHO NEED IT MOST PARTICULARLY FOCUSING ON OLDER ADULTS
AND THOSE WITH MENTAL OR PHYSICAL HEALTH CONDITIONS.
>> THE ORGANIZATION MAY HAVE BEGUN BECAUSE OF FRANCIS FORD
COPPOLA BUT IT HAS ENDURED BECAUSE OF CHRISTIE.
>> CHRISTIE HAS AN INCREDIBLE ABILITY TO MEET SOMEONE ON THE
STREET SOMEONE OFTEN IN THE DARKEST CHAPTER OF THEIR LIVES
AND CENTER THE HUMANITY AND VALUE THAT EXISTS IN THEM.
SHE BALANCES CARE AND COMPASSION WITH A
RELENTLESS FOCUS OF MOVING PEOPLE FORWARD FROM HELPING
THEM OBTAIN THEIR BENEFITS TO ACCESSING CARE TO EVENTUALLY
SECURING STABLE HOUSING. AND CHRISTIE, I KNOW THAT
PEOPLE HAVE OFTEN SAID THAT WE NEED A NORTH BEACH CITIZENS FOR
EVERY NEIGHBORHOOD BUT THAT WOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE BECAUSE WE
CAN'T REPLICATE YOU FOR EVERY NEIGHBORHOOD.
YOU ARE TRULY AT THE HEART AND CENTER OF THIS AND WE ARE
GRATEFUL AND IN DEBT TO YOU. >> WHAT I REALLY APPRECIATE
ABOUT NORTH BEACH CITIZENS IS HOW FOCUSED THEY REMAIN ON THE
NEEDS OF THOSE IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD WHILE OTHER
ORGANIZATIONS CHOOSE TO GROW WIDER AND MIGHT LOSE THEIR
PERSONAL TOUCH, NORTH BEACH CITIZENS INSTEAD HAS DECIDED
DELIBERATELY TO GROW DEEPER AND TO REALLY CEMENT THEIR
IMPACT IN THE NORTH BEACH NEIGHBORHOOD.
>> THEY DO SO IN LARGE PART BECAUSE OF THEIR INCREDIBLE
STAFF, VOLUNTEERS AND BOARD MEMBERS.
IT CONTINUES TO BE SOME 25 YEARS LATER.
NOW A NEIGHBORHOOD BASED APPROACHED A NEIGHBORHOOD BASED
APPROACH TO WHAT IS REALLY A GLOBAL CHALLENGE.
AND BECAUSE OF THIS NORTH BEACH CITIZENS HAS INCREDIBLE TRUST,
INTEGRITY AND SUPPORT IN OUR COMMUNITY.
CHRISTIE WAS REALLY GOOD TO JOIN YOU THE OTHER WEEK TO
CELEBRATE 25 YEARS AT YOUR GALA.
THANK YOU FOR THE WORK YOU DO EVERY SINGLE DAY IN WAYS SMALL
IN WAYS LARGE. >> CONGRATULATIONS.
THE FLOOR IS YOURS TO SAY A FEW WORDS NOW.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH. CHRISTIE IF I COULD JUST ADD.
>> SURE. I AND I WANT TO THANK YOU
SUPERVISOR SAUTER FOR DOING THIS COMMENDATION.
YOUR YOUR IMPACT AND INFLUENCE OF COURSE IS MOST FELT IN NORTH
BEACH AND IN DISTRICT THREE BUT BUT YOUR INFLUENCE IS FELT
CITYWIDE AND EARLY ON WHEN I JOINED THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
MY PREDECESSOR BEVAN DUFTY TOLD ME THAT I NEEDED TO GO TALK TO
CHRISTIE FAIRCHILD IN NORTH BEACH AND SEE WHAT THEY WERE
DOING AT NORTH BEACH CITIZENS AND YOU WERE SO GENEROUS WITH
YOUR TIME AND SHOWING ME THE AMAZING WORK THAT YOU DO THERE
WITH UNHOUSED PEOPLE IN NORTH BEACH AND IT'S JUST IT'S BEEN A
JOY TO BE ABLE TO KNOW YOU, TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE DOING THE WORK
YOU'RE DOING IN SAN FRANCISCO. AND SO THANK YOU FOR YOU KNOW,
YOU ALL OF YOUR AMAZINGNESS. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR SAUTER FOR DOING THIS.
IT'S SUCH AN HONOR TO BE WITH ALL OF YOU AND THANK YOU ALL OF
YOU FOR YOUR DEDICATED SERVICE AND MY BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
WE REALLY GREATLY APPRECIATE YOUR PARTNERSHIP.
I KIND OF HAD SOME WRITTEN WORDS YOU KIND OF SAID A LOT OF
WHAT I WAS GOING TO SAY BUT I DO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE MY STAFF
CRYSTAL LEE AND ADAM AND GINA FOR THEIR DEDICATED WORK ON
BEHALF OF OUR UNHOUSED AND EXTREMELY LOW INCOME
INDIVIDUALS THAT WE SERVE EACH DAY.
AND IT REALLY IS A TESTAMENT I WOULD SAY AS YOU WERE
MENTIONING FRANCIS WAS IN THE BUILDING TO MEET THE MAYOR,
GAVE HIM A LITTLE BIT OF TIME AND THAT WAS REALLY WONDERFUL
FOR BOTH OF THEM. AND AT THE HEART OF IT IT
REALLY WAS A COMMITMENT AGAIN TO WHAT WE SEE AND WHAT THIS
ORGANIZATION HAS ALWAYS BEEN BASED ON IS THAT THE
NEIGHBORHOODS KNOW EXACTLY WHAT IS NEEDED BY THEIR CONSTITU
AND YOU BRING THAT UP HERE INTO CITY HALL TO REPRESENT YOUR
CONSTITUENTS AND WE DO THE SAME THING ON A DAILY BASIS AND IT
REALLY IS OUR GREATEST PLEASURE TO HELP THOSE AND HAVE THEM
AND TRUST US WITH THEIR MOST INTIMATE NEEDS AND CONCERNS
AND IT IS OUR COMMITMENT TO HELP WITH OUR CASE MANAGEMENT,
OUR BASED ON HOUSING AND ALSO OUR FOOD PANTRY AND OUR STREET
BEAUTIFICATION PROGRAM. SO IT REALLY IS A WONDERFUL
HONOR. I JUST WANTED TO SAY THANK YOU
AND WE REALLY APPRECIATE THIS RECOGNITION
. >> ALL RIGHT, COLLEAGUES, TODAY
WE ARE HONORING TWO EXCEPTIONAL PUBLIC SERVANTS FROM OUR
DEPARTMENT OF EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AND I WOULD LIKE TO
INVITE OH, THAT'S RIGHT, TEAM. WE HAVE KAREN COLLINS GRACE,
COME ON UP. >> THE DEPARTMENT'S 2025
DISPATCHER OF THE YEAR AND WE HAVE ZOILA LA CHUGGA.
>> ZOILA, ARE YOU THERE? COME ON UP.
>> ZOILA IS THE DEPARTMENT'S LEAD DE SHIFT TRAINING
SUPERVISOR AND THE 2025 RECIPIENT OF THE TONY HARDLEY
AWARD FOR EXCELLENCE IN SUPERVISION AND I'M GOING TO
SAY NICE THINGS ABOUT YOU CAN SIT IF YOU LIKE OR STAND IF YOU
LIKE. KAREN CALLENDER'S IS WORK AS
A911 DISPATCHER HAS DEMONSTRATED BOTH TACTICAL
PROFICIENCY AND DECISIVENESS IN COORDINATING EMERGENCY
RESPONSE TO EXTREMELY DIFFICULT SITUATIONS.
THIS PAST YEAR SHE HANDLED A SERIES OF FAST MOVING HIGH
INTENSITY INCIDENTS ON POLICE RADIO CHANNEL EIGHT SIX WHICH
IS WIDELY REGARDED AS REGARDED AS ONE OF THE BUSIEST AND MOST
DEMANDING CHANNELS IN THE CITY DURING ONE PARTICULARLY
CHALLENGING SHIFT, KAREN EXPERTLY MANAGED MULTIPLE
CRITICAL INCIDENTS UNFOLDING SIMULTANEOUSLY.
>> IT BEGAN WITH A VIOLENT ROBBERY OUTSIDE THE CHINESE
HOSPITAL EMERGENCY ROOM AND AN ASSAULT ON A U.S. PARK POLICE
OFFICER AS A SECOND ROBBERY BY THE SAME SUSPECTS WAS OBSERVED
LIVE BY A POLICE DRONE UNIT. KAREN RELAYED REAL TIME SUSPECT
DESCRIPTIONS AND DIRECTED MULTI-UNIT RESPONSES IN THE
MIDDLE OF ALL THE CHAOS AN UNIDENTIFIED UNIT CALLED OUT A
PERSON RESISTING WITHOUT PROVIDING A LOCATION.
KAREN HANDLED IT FLAWLESSLY. SHE CALMLY REPEATED THE
TRANSMISSION QUICKLY CONFIRMED THE LOCATION AND BROADCAST IT
TO ALL RESPONDING UNITS TO RESTORE ORDER IN AN EXTREMELY
CHAOTIC SITUATION WHEN AN OFFICER WAS INJURED, SHE
IMMEDIATELY PRIORITIZED MEDICAL AID MAKING SURE PARAMEDICS WERE
DISPATCHED CODE THREE TO THE SCENE KAREN'S OUTSTANDING
JUDGMENT AND SKILL ENSURED THE SAFETY OF ALL OFFICERS WHILE
CONTRIBUTING TO THE SUCCESSFUL APPREHENSION OF DANGEROUS
SUSPECTS. HER PERFORMANCE WAS SO
EXCEPTIONAL THAT RETIRED ASSISTANT CHIEF DAVID LAZAAR
PERSONALLY CALLED IN TO COMMEND HER WORK, STATING IT WAS ONE OF
THE MOST PROFESSIONAL DISPATCHES HE'D HEARD IN HIS
CAREER. >> HER EXCELLENT WORK EARNED
KAREN AUGUST'S DISPATCHER OF THE MONTH RECOGNITION AND THEN
SHE WAS LATER AWARDED THE 2020 THE 2025 DISPATCHER OF THE YEAR
. NO MATTER THE MAGNITUDE OF THE
PROBLEM, KAREN'S HARD WORK AND DEDICATION TO KEEPING ALL
INVOLVED PARTIES SAFE MORE THAN MERITS RECOGNITION IN A SOCIETY
WHERE WE RELY ON 911 DISPATCHERS TO HANDLE SUCH
SITUATIONS WITH URGENCY, KAREN PERFECTLY SETS THE STANDARD FOR
DISPATCHER RESPONSE NOW ZOILA FOR YEARS ZOILA LA SHUGA HAS
DEMONSTRATED A CONSISTENT COMMITMENT TO LEARNING
AND SHARING KNOWLEDGE AND BEING A FIERCE ADVOCATE FOR THE
WELL-BEING OF HER TEAM. SHE SUPPORTS HER COWORKERS
THROUGH THE BAD DAYS SO THEY CAN BE CALM.
VOICES ON THE LINE ON CALLERS WORST DAYS.
THROUGH HER LEADERSHIP IN WELLNESS AND PEER SUPPORT
SHE ENSURES THAT NO ONE IN THE DEPARTMENT EVER FEELS THEY HAVE
TO HANDLE THE STRESS OF THE JOB ALONE.
HER COLLEAGUES DESCRIBE HER AS SOMEONE WHO MAKES THEM FEEL
HEARD AND SUPPORTER SUPPORTED AND WHO PROVIDES THOUGHTFUL
KNOWLEDGE AND STEADY LEADERSHIP TO PEERS.
SO ELLA ALWAYS SHOWS UP FOR THE OPERATIONS FLOOR WHETHER IT IS
MONITORING RUNS, RESOLVING SCHEDULING ISSUES OR ENSURING
THAT TRAINEES FEEL CONFIDENT AS THEY BUILD THEIR FUTURES AT
TEAM. SHE'S BEEN A QUIET CHAMPION
BEHIND SAN FRANCISCO'S EMERGENCY EMERGENCY LIFELINE
SUPPORTING THE FLOOR WITH HER VISION AND COMPASSION, ZOILA
APPLIED HER JOB KNOWLEDGE AND COMMITMENT TO REVAMPING THE
TEAM'S PEER SUPPORT AND WELLNESS TEAMS.
SHE WROTE COUNTLESS PROPOSALS AND SECURED FUNDING FOR
CERTIFIED TRAINING AND FIRST RESPONDER THERAPY AND EVEN
ESTABLISHED A NEW WELLNESS ROOM FOR STAFF TO DECOMPRESS AFTER
TRAUMATIC CALLS. SHE'S ALSO AN EFFECTIVE
COLLABORATOR WITH THE POLICE DEPARTMENT AND THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT ENSURING OUR DISPATCHERS ARE NOW INCLUDED
IN CRITICAL INCIDENT DEBRIEFS. >> THE TONY HARDLEY DISPATCH
SUPERVISOR AWARD IS NAMED AFTER THE LATE TONY HARTLEY WHO WAS
WIDELY RESPECTED AND SEEN AS A MOTHER FIGURE FOR MANY
DISPATCHERS, ZOILA ZOILA IS HARD WORK AND DEDICATION
REFLECT THE QUALITIES THAT TONY STOOD FOR AND SHE NOW EMBODIES
THOSE IN HER WORK BY RECOGNIZING THE STRENGTHS
IN OTHERS AND HELPING THEM SHINE.
KAREN AND ZOILA, WE ARE GRATEFUL FOR YOUR SERVICE TO
SAN FRANCISCO AND APPRECIATE YOUR MAGNIFICENT WORK ETHIC
WITHIN THE DEPARTMENT OF EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AND I
THINK I THINK MARY ELLEN IS BACK THERE SOMEWHERE AND IF
SHE'D LIKE TO COME FORWARD AND ADD ANY WORDS YOU'RE
WELCOME TO. >> MARY ELLEN CARROLL, DIRECTOR
OF THE DEPARTMENT OF EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT.
HI. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISORS. I JUST WANTED WELL, FIRST OF
ALL, I WANT TO SAY I'M LOVING THIS REDO OF WOMEN'S HISTORY
MONTH WITH ALL THE WOMEN THAT WE AMAZING AMAZING WOMEN WE'RE
HONORING TODAY. I JUST WANT TO THANK ALL OF YOU
FOR TAKING THE MOMENT TO RECOGNIZE THESE AMAZING PUBLIC
SERVANTS. THEY ARE PART OF OUR PUBLIC
SAFETY ORGANIZATION FOR THIS CITY BUT THEY DON'T GET SEEN
LITERALLY SEEN PHYSICALLY AS MUCH SO EVERY YEAR THAT YOU DO
THIS IT'S MUCH APPRECIATED THE STORIES TELL THEMSELVES
AND THESE TWO WOMEN HAVE MUCH MORE IMPORTANT THINGS TO SAY
THAN I AM. >> I DO SO I'M GOING TO LEAVE
IT TO THEM. >> ALL RIGHT.
COME ON UP. >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
>> I AM DEEPLY HONORED TO RECEIVE THE TONY HARLEY
SUPERVISOR OF THE YEAR AWARD BEING RECOGNIZED BY MY PEERS
FOR MY DEDICATION TO SUPPORTING WELLNESS TRULY REFLECTS THE
POSITIVE PROGRESS WE ARE MAKING TOGETHER.
SPEAKING ABOUT MY ACCOMPLISHMENTS IS SOMEWHAT
CHALLENGING BECAUSE MY EFFORTS IN CREATING, STRENGTHENING
AND STRENGTHENING THESE PROGRAMS HAVE ALWAYS BEEN
FOCUSED ON SUPPORTING THE DISPATCHERS I WORK ALONGSIDE.
IT WAS NEVER MEANT OR ABOUT PERSONAL RECOGNITION SO I
REMAIN GENUINELY HUMBLED BY THIS PUBLIC SAFETY DISPATCHERS
ARE OFTEN UNSEEN ONLY HEARD. WE'VE ALL HEARD THAT BEFORE.
WE HAVE ALSO HEARD THEM CALL THE FIRST FIRST RESPONDERS TO
EMERGENCIES AND THEY ARE THAT THE VERY FIRST POINT OF CONTACT
WHEN THE CITIZENS OF SAN FRANCISCO CALL IN FOR HELP THEY
ANSWER CALLS FROM DIFFERENT THINGS THAT MIGHT BE GOING ON.
IT COULD BE A DEVASTATED PARENT WHOSE INFANT IS UNCONSCIOUS
AND NOT BREATHING OR A CITIZEN OF DOMESTIC VIOLENCE WHO IS
BROKEN, SCARED, HURT AND UNSURE OF HOW TO ASK FOR HELP.
IT IS A DISPATCHER WHO PROVIDES LIFESAVING INSTRUCTIONS OR
BECOMES THE CALMING STRONG VOICE THAT A VICTIM DESPERATELY
NEEDS THE TRAUMA THAT PUBLIC SAFETY DISPATCHERS FACE DAILY
IS IMMENSE, OFTEN UNRECOGNIZED OR UNADDRESSED UNTIL IT'S TOO
LATE. THE EXPOSURE CHANGES YOU
TRANSFORMING THE PERSON THAT YOU WERE ONCE BEFORE STARTING
YOUR CAREER AS A DISPATCHER. THERE IS ALSO A COMMON
MISCONCEPTION THAT BECAUSE DISPATCHERS NOT PHYSICALLY
DISPATCHED TO THE SCENE THEY DO NOT ENDURE THE SAME TRAUMA AS
OTHER FIRST RESPONDERS. BUT THAT'S NOT ENTIRELY TRUE.
DURING TRAINING DISPATCHERS ARE TAUGHT TO PAINT THE PICTURE SO
THEY'RE RESPONDING. UNITS HAVE A CLEAR
UNDERSTANDING OF THE SITUATION BUT WHAT EXACTLY DOES THAT MEAN
WHEN YOU PAINT A PICTURE JUST AS A DISPATCHER YOU ARE
ACTUALLY TRANSPORTING YOURSELF TO THAT SCENE.
YOU SEE WHAT THEY SEE, YOU HEAR WHAT THEY HEAR, YOU FEEL WHAT
THEY FEEL. YOU EXPERIENCE THE RUSH OF
ADRENALINE. YOU FEEL YOUR TIGHT YOUR
MUSCLES TIGHTEN AND YOU ARE PROBABLY HEARING ONE OF THE
WORST DAYS OF THAT PERSON'S LIFE YET THEY REMAIN CALM.
FOCUS ON ASKING THE RIGHT QUESTIONS, CONTROL THE CALLER,
DOCUMENT EVERYTHING THAT THEY HEAR AND THEN HELP ARRIVES.
ONCE THAT HELP ARRIVES YOU DISCONNECT THAT CALL.
YOU'RE ONLY LEFT WITH THE IMAGES AND THE SOUND AND YOUR
VOICES WITH NO CLOSURE. NOW IMAGINE TAKING CALLS AFTER
CALLS LIKE THIS. >> THIS IS PRECISELY WHY PEER
SUPPORT AND WELLNESS PROGRAMS ARE VITAL AND ANY PUBLIC SAFETY
COMMUNICATION CENTER AND WHY AM DEEPLY COMMITTED TO THE
WELL-BEING OF OUR DISPATCHERS HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
IT'S ALSO WHY I REACH OUT TO THE NEWLY HIRED DISPATCHERS
AND WHY I HAVE BEEN SO INVOLVED IN TRAINING TO ENSURE THAT THEY
KNOW EARLY IN THEIR CAREERS THAT SUPPORT AND RESOURCES ARE
AVAILABLE. >> I AM INCREDIBLY FORTUNATE
THAT MY UPPER MANAGEMENT AT THE DEPARTMENT OF EMERGENCY
MANAGEMENT HAS BEEN UNWAVERINGLY SUPPORTIVE
WHENEVER I'VE BROUGHT FORWARD PROPOSALS OR IDEAS.
SO I WANT TO TAKE THE OPPORTUNITY TO THANK THEM FOR
THEIR UNDERSTANDING AND COMMITMENT TO THE MENTAL
HEALTH OF OUR DISPATCHERS. I ALSO WANT TO THANK THE
SUPERVISORS I WORK WITH WHO NEVER COMPLAIN WHEN I'M TIED UP
WITH PROJECTS OR UNAVAILABLE ON THE FLOOR AND WHO ALWAYS OFFER
A SHOULDER TO LEAN ON WHEN I MOST NEED IT TO THE DEDICATED
DISPATCHERS ALWAYS READY TO TAKE THE NEXT CALL AND BE A
LIFELINE TO CITIZENS AND FIELD MEMBERS ALIKE.
YOUR STRENGTH MOTIVATES ME EVERY DAY.
LASTLY TO MY FAMILY MY HUSBAND, MY SISTER, MY BIGGEST
SUPPORTERS, MY CHEERLEADERS AND CORE STRENGTH.
>> I WOULDN'T BE HERE WITHOUT YOU GUYS.
THANK YOU ALL. KAREN COME ON UP.
GOOD AFTERNOON. THANK YOU.
I'M TRULY HONORED TO STAND BEFORE THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
TO RECEIVE THIS RECOGNITION THIS VETERAN OF THE YEAR AWARD
AND THANK YOU ALL FOR BEING HERE.
>> CAN YOU PLEASE SPEAK DIRECTLY INTO THE MICROPHONES
SO WE CAN HEAR YOU BEST? >> SORRY.
THE PROBLEM THANK YOU FOR THIS RECOGNITION.
THANK YOU FOR THE WORDS FROM NOW RETIRED ASSISTANT CHIEF
DAVID LESSARD. HIS WORDS MEANT THE WORK TO ME
AND I APPRECIATE THE REASON WHY I'M HERE THIS YEAR AS WELL.
BUT BEING A DISPATCHER IS A UNIQUE KIND OF SERVICE.
IT'S WE ARE THE CALM VOICE LIKE ZOILA SAID BEHIND THE SCENES WE
MIGHT NEVER BE SEEN BUT WE'RE ALWAYS ALWAYS THERE.
WE ARE LISTENING GUIDING, SUPPORTING NOT ONLY THE PUBLIC
BUT OUR UNITS IN THE FIELD AND THE PARTNERS THAT WE WORK
WITH. THERE'S A WAY IT'S NOT JUST
ABOUT ME. IT'S ABOUT A GROUP OF DIVERSE
AND INCREDIBLE PEOPLE THAT I WORK WITH IN THIS PLACE.
SO THIS JOB IS ABOUT THE PEOPLE THAT YOU WORK WITH.
EVENTUALLY THEY BECOME FAMILY. SORRY.
AND THEY'RE THE ONES THAT MY FELLOW DISPATCHERS YOU ARE THE
BACKBONE OF PUBLIC SAFETY. WE ARE ALWAYS THERE.
WE ARE THERE ELSEWHERE. HOPE IN THIS JOB AGAIN LIKE I
SAID IS FOR THOSE THAT PEOPLE THAT WE WORK WITH AND WE KEEP
GOING AND SHOWING UP FOR THEM AND WHEN WE FIRST START WE LOOK
FOR SOMEONE TO TAKE US UNDER THEIR WING TO GIVE US SOME
GUIDANCE TOO. >> AND I WAS LUCKY TO GET SO
MANY MAMAS OUT THERE AND 20 YEARS LATER YOU FIND YOURSELF
IN YOUR MOM ERA. >> NOW YOU'RE THE MAMA THEN
GIVE ME HOPE THAT MEANS THAT ARE HERE.
THANK YOU. YOU GUYS KEEP ME ON MY TOES
WITH YOUR RANDOM QUESTIONS, WITH YOUR EXCITEMENT, WITH YOUR
EMERGENCIES NOW WITH JUST PULLING UP A CHAIR AND SHARING
MY CHAIR WITH ME AND YOUR STORIES.
>> I LOVE YOU BECAUSE YOU GUYS REMIND ME WHY I LOVE THIS JOB.
I LOVE THIS JOB. AND TO MY FELLOW OG DISPATCHERS
,THANK YOU FOR HELPING ME KEEP MY SANITY.
>> YOU READ THROUGH 20 YEARS AND STILL LIKE I WAS HIGH ON
THIS MATTRESS. LOVE YOU.
LOVE YOU FOR BEING HERE TO AGAIN YOU ARE THE REASON WHY I
KEPT MY SANITY THROUGH THIS YEARS.
I ALSO WANT TO THANK THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE OFFICERS,
FIREFIGHTERS, SHERIFFS AND EMS DEPARTMENT PERSONNEL THAT WE
SUPPORT IS THE TRUST AND TEAMWORK THAT WE SHARE THAT
MAKES THIS SYSTEM WORK WITH SOME ROOM FOR IMPROVEMENT OF
COURSE, BUT WE MAKE IT WORK AND TO MY SISTER, MY LOVED ONES
,MY DRACO, MY THREE DOGS ARE MY TWO CATS.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR PATIENCE .
THANK YOU FOR UNDERSTANDING THE LONG HOURS MY MOOD SWINGS THAT
CRAZY SCHEDULES I LOVE YOU MORE AND I'M DEEPLY GRATEFUL FOR
THIS RECOGNITION. I LIKE I SAID I CAN EXPRESS IT
AND ANY BETTER AND I WILL CONTINUE TO SERVE WITH PRIDE,
DEDICATION AND HEART AND AT THE END OF THE DAY IT ALL COMES
DOWN TO ONE THING THAT WE ALL GO HOME SAFELY AT THE END OF
OUR SHIFTS. >> THANK YOU.
APPRECIATE IT. THANK YOU, MARY ELLEN.
I KNOW I GOT TIME RIGHT? >> ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT. SO WE DO OKAY.
ALL RIGHT. THESE THE SELFIE AND YOU TAKE A
PHOTO, TAKE IT. THERE WE GO.
OKAY. TWO, THREE, TWO.
THANK YOU. OKAY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH. ALL RIGHT.
>> I THINK THAT TAKES US TO ROLL CALL, MADAM CLERK.
YES, THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. >> SUPERVISOR MELGAR, YOUR
FIRST STEP TO INTRODUCE NEW BUSINESS AND THANK YOU.
I WOULD LIKE TO BE REFERRED AFTER SUPERVISOR CHERYL SPEAK
PLEASE. >> AND THE REST I WILL SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MELGAR, SUPERVISOR SADR.
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. >> COLLEAGUES TODAY I AM
INTRODUCING A PACKAGE ESTABLISHING FOUR NEW
ENTERTAINMENT ZONES ACROSS DISTRICT THREE.
>> THIS REPRESENTS THE WORK OF CONVERSATIONS WITH STAKEHOLDERS
ACROSS MANY OF OUR BUSINESS DISTRICTS OVER THE PAST YEAR
AND THIS PACKAGE WILL INCLUDE NEW ENTERTAINMENT ZONES FOR
NORTH BEACH, THE FERRY BUILDING ,EMBARCADERO PLAZA AND BELDEN
PLACE IN OUR DOWNTOWN CORE. I THINK WE HAVE ALL SEEN THE
PROMISE OF ENTERTAINMENT ZONES ACROSS OUR CITY AND ACROSS OUR
RESPECTIVE DISTRICTS. THEY MEAN MORE LIFE IN OUR
STREETS, MORE FOOT TRAFFIC IN OUR NEIGHBORHOODS
AND IMPORTANTLY MORE DOLLARS IN THE POCKETS OF OUR SMALL
BUSINESS OWNERS. ENTERTAINMENT ZONES ARE OF
COURSE JUST ONE TOOL IN OUR EFFORT TO MAKE THINGS EASIER
FOR SMALL BUSINESSES IN OUR CITY.
AND OUR OFFICE IS FULLY COMMITTED TO ALL PULLING ALL
THE LEVERS WE HAVE BE IT LOWERING PERMITTING HURDLES,
CLARIFYING CONFUSING CODES, PROVIDING SAFER AND CLEANER
CONDITIONS ON OUR STREETS AND SIDEWALKS AND BRINGING
TARGETED INVESTMENTS TO ECONOMICALLY CHALLENGED
CORRIDORS. I WANT TO GIVE THANKS TO
MICHELE ANDREWS IN MY OFFICE BEN VAN HOUTEN IN CASEY YOU ALL
THE CHICK FROM ALL IWD AND VICKY WONG IN THE CITY
ATTORNEY'S OFFICE FOR THEIR HARD WORK TO BRING THESE NEW
ENTERTAINMENT ZONES TO LIFE. MOST IMPORTANTLY, THANKS TO
EACH SET OF SMALL BUSINESSES AND NEIGHBORHOOD GROUPS WHO
WE'VE COLLABORATED WITH. AND THAT IS FOR NORTH BEACH,
THE NORTH BEACH BUSINESSES ASSOCIATION FOR THE FERRY
BUILDING, HUDSON PACIFIC FOR THE EMBARCADERO PLAZA BSP
AND FOR BELDEN PLACE THE DOWNTOWN S.F. PARTNERSHIP.
WE CAN'T WAIT TO SEE THE CREATIVITY AND ENERGY THAT
THESE NEW ENTERTAINMENT ZONES WILL HELP UNLEASH.
>> AND THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR SAUTER SUPERVISOR CHERYL COLLEAGUES TODAY
ALONGSIDE SUPERVISOR MELGAR I'M PROUD TO INTRODUCE A RESOLUTION
THAT RECOGNIZES APRIL 2026 AS NATIONAL SEXUAL ASSAULT
AWARENESS AND PREVENTION MONTH HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
SEXUAL ASSAULT REMAINS A PERVASIVE PUBLIC HEALTH ISSUE
THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY AND THE WORLD AFFECTING INDIVIDUALS OF
ALL AGES, GENDERS AND BACKGROUNDS.
IT IS A HEARTBREAKING CRISIS. EVERY 68 SECONDS SOMEONE IN THE
UNITED STATES IS SEXUALLY ASSAULTED.
AND IN LIGHT OF RECENT NEWS HERE IN CALIFORNIA, IT IS
CRITICAL THAT WE AS A BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ALL JOIN TO
REAFFIRM OUR COMMITMENT TO BRINGING THIS CRISIS OUT OF THE
DARK. SUPPORTING SURVIVORS OF SEXUAL
ASSAULT AND RAISING AWARENESS ABOUT SUPPORT SYSTEMS FOR
VICTIMS, SURVIVORS AND THEIR LOVED ONES.
I'M GRATEFUL FOR THE EARLY SUPPORT OF SO MANY OF OUR
COLLEAGUES SUPERVISOR CHEN, PRESIDENT MANDELL MEN
AND OTHERS ON THIS BOARD WHO'VE ALREADY JOINED AS CO-SPONSORS
TO THIS RESOLUTION. >> WE NEED TO REALIZE THAT
PUBLIC SAFETY YES IS ABOUT A FULLY STAFFED POLICE
DEPARTMENT. BUT IT'S NOT JUST ABOUT THAT.
IT IS ABOUT MUCH, MUCH MORE. IT IS ABOUT SUPPORTING A
COMMUNITY OF PROVIDERS, A COMMUNITY OF ADVOCATES, A
COMMUNITY OF SURVIVORS WHO CONTINUOUSLY STEP UP TIME
AND AGAIN. BY PASSING THIS RESOLUTION WE
THANK THE ADVOCATES WHO TIRELESSLY DEDICATE THEIR LIVES
TO STOPPING SEXUAL VIOLENCE AND SUPPORTING SURVIVORS.
AND WE MAKE IT CLEAR THAT SAN FRANCISCO REMAINS DEDICATED TO
CREATING SAFER COMMUNITIES FOR EVERYONE.
>> THE REST I SUBMIT. THANK YOU SUPERVISORS SHERYL
AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR SHERYL FOR INTRODUCING BEING AT THIS
RESOLUTION. I AM JOINING SUPERVISOR SHERYL
SACCO SPONSOR AND THIS IS THE TIME FOR US TO RECOGNIZE
SURVIVORS TO CONFRONT DIFFICULT TRUTHS TO COMMIT.
WE COMMIT OURSELVES TO DISMANTLING A SYSTEM AND A
CULTURE THAT HAS ALLOWED FOR SEXUAL ASSAULT AND ABUSE TO BE
NORMALIZED WITHIN OUR CITY, WITHIN OUR PROGRESSIVE
MOVEMENT, WITHIN OUR LABOR MOVEMENTS, WITHIN OUR POLITICAL
CIRCLES. SEXUAL VIOLENCE IS PREVALENT.
IT'S OFTEN HIDDEN. IT PROTECTS THOSE WHO ARE
IN POWER. IT IS IMPORTANT THAT WE SPEAK
OPENLY AND THAT WE BACK OUR WORDS WITH CONVICTION.
SURVIVORS WILL BE BELIEVED AND PERPETRATE.
>> LEADERS WILL BE HELD ACCOUNTABLE.
IT HAS BEEN A VERY PAINFUL AND CHALLENGING TIME FOR US
THIS LAST THESE LAST FEW WEEKS OF LAST MONTH WITHIN THE LATINO
COMMUNITY IN CALIFORNIA, WITHIN ALL OF US.
>> IT IS YET AGAIN THAT WE'RE HEARING FROM SURVIVORS WHO ARE
RISKING EVERYTHING THEIR CAREERS, THEIR LIVES TO STOP
PREDATORS FROM CONTINUING TO VICTIMIZE OTHERS AS LEADERS.
>> THOSE OF US IN A POSITION OF POWER MUST DO EVERYTHING SO
THAT WE CAN ENSURE THAT OUR SYSTEMS ARE NOT USED TO PROTECT
PREDATORS RATHER THAN THEY ARE USED TO PROTECT THE DIGNITY OF
EVERY PERSON. I WANT TO THANK THE YOUTH
COMMISSION AND ORGANIZERS FOR THEIR CONSISTENT ADVOCACY ON
THIS VERY IMPORTANT ISSUE. OF COURSE THE OFFICE OF VICTIMS
RIGHTS AND SHARP TO YOUNG PEOPLE.
WE HAVE TO DO BETTER AND FULFILL OUR PROMISE TO
CREATE A SAFE SPACE OR SEXUAL ABUSE AND HARASSMENT CLAIMS ARE
TAKEN SERIOUSLY AND THAT NO ONE IS LEFT NOT KNOWING WHERE TO
TURN. >> MOREOVER, WE NEED TO INVEST
IN RESOURCES TO SUPPORT YOUNG PEOPLE SO THAT THEY ARE ABLE TO
DEVELOP HEALTHY RELATIONSHIPS, UNDERSTAND CONSENT, RESPECT SO
THAT WE CAN END THIS HORRIBLE CYCLE OF SEXUAL VIOLENCE.
CHANGE WILL NOT HAPPEN THROUGH STATEMENTS OR RESOLUTIONS.
WE AS A SOCIETY HAVE TO CHOOSE WHAT WE CHOOSE TO CHALLENGE
WHAT WE CHOOSE TO ACCEPT. NOT PERFORMATIVE NESS BUT
RATHER ACTION. THANK YOU.
THE REST I SUBMIT. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
SUPERVISOR WALTON SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR WONG. GOOD AFTERNOON COLLEAGUES.
TODAY AT THE REQUEST OF WHICH RETIREMENT PRACTICE FAMILY I'M
HONORED TO INTRODUCE A RESOLUTION RECOGNIZING THE LIFE
AND LEGACY OF MR. WATANABE AND REAFFIRMING OUR CITY'S
COMMITMENT TO ELDER SAFETY, VIOLENCE PREVENTION
AND STANDING AGAINST A HATE MR. TANNER PARTY KNOWN TO MANY AS
GRANDPA VICTOR WAS A BELOVED FATHER AND GRANDFATHER.
HE WAS SOMEONE WHO FOUND JOY IN SIMPLE ROUTINES LIKE HIS
MORNING WALKS AND WAS A QUIET BUT MEANINGFUL PRESENCE IN HIS
NEIGHBORHOOD. FIVE YEARS AGO HE WAS TAKEN
FROM US IN AN ACT OF VIOLENCE DURING ONE OF HIS MORNING WALKS
HIS PASSING WAS A PROFOUND LOSS FOR HIS FAMILY AND DEEPLY
AFFECTED COMMUNITIES ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO.
LIKE MANY IN OUR CITY, I REMEMBER HOW DEEPLY THIS MOMENT
WAS FELT. IT SHOOK A SENSE OF SAFETY THAT
SO MANY OF OUR SENIORS RELY ON AND IT STAYED WITH FAMILIES WHO
SAW THEIR OWN LOVED ONES IN HIM.
AT THE TIME HIS DEATH CAME AMID A SHARP RISE IN VIOLENCE
ESPECIALLY IMPACTING OUR SENIORS.
FOR MANY FAMILIES IT BROUGHT FEAR CLOSER TO HOME
AND REMINDED US HOW MUCH MORE WE MUST DO TO ENSURE SAFETY
AND DIGNITY FOR ALL. BUT HIS LEGACY DID NOT END
THERE. MR. PATTI'S STORY BROUGHT
COMMUNITIES TOGETHER, RAISED AWARENESS ABOUT THE SAFETY OF
OUR ELDERS AND REMINDED US OF THE RESPONSIBILITY WE SHARE TO
LOOK OUT FOR ONE ANOTHER. TODAY HIS NAME CONTINUES TO
LIVE ON IN OUR CITY AND IN THE ONGOING WORK TO BUILD SAFER,
MORE CONNECTED COMMUNITIES. THIS RESOLUTION HONORS HIS LIFE
EXTENDS OUR CONDOLENCES TO HIS FAMILY AND RECOGNIZES THE
LASTING IMPACT OF HIS LOSS. IT ALSO REAFFIRMS OUR
RESPONSIBILITY AS A CITY TO ENSURE THAT ALL SENIORS CAN
MOVE SAFELY THROUGH THEIR NEIGHBORHOODS AND TO CONTINUE
INVESTING IN PREVENTION, COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT
AND HEALING. I ALSO WANT TO THANK
SUPERVISORS CHERYL SAUTER AND DORSEY FOR THEIR EARLY
CO-SPONSORSHIP AND SUPPORT. WE MUST CONTINUE WORKING
TOGETHER WITH OUR COMMUNITY PARTNERS, PUBLIC PUBLIC SAFETY
AGENCIES AND FAMILIES TO ENSURE THAT WHAT HAPPENED FIVE YEARS
AGO IS NEVER REPEATED. COLLEAGUES I RESPECTFULLY ASK
FOR YOUR SUPPORT. THE REST I SUBMIT THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WANG.
SUPERVISOR CHEN SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHEN. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK, FOR
CALLING TODAY. I'M INTRODUCING A HEARING
REQUEST ON THE PROPOSED STATE BUDGET DECISIONS IMPACTING OUR
HOMELESSNESS AND SUPPORTIVE HOUSING SYSTEM OF CARE.
>> WE KNOW THAT THE HOMELESSNESS CRISIS IS COMPLEX.
WE KNOW THAT DIFFERENT ADMINISTRATIONS AND OFFICES
HAVE EMPLOYED A DIFFERENT TOOLS AND TACTIC TO TRY AND TO
ADDRESS THESE ISSUES. >> BUT REGARDLESS OF WHICH
SCHOOL OF THOUGHT WE FALL INTO, I HOPE WE CAN AGREE THAT WE
WANT TO SOLVE THIS ISSUES WITH EFFICACY AND COMPASSION.
LAST WEEK MISSION LOCO REPORTED THAT WE ARE GOING TO LOSE MORE
THAN 450 SHELTER BEDS. >> I HAVE ALSO HEARD THAT THERE
PLANS TO DO COMMISSIONS PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING
UNITS. AT THE SAME TIME WE ARE STILL
FACING A DEFICIT THAT NEEDS TO BE ADJUSTED AND THEY ARE
LOOMING AND DETERMINED A THREAT TO THE STATE AND FEDERAL FUNDS
FOR HOUSING. >> I HAVE CONCERNS ABOUT HOW WE
ARE PLANNING TO ENSURE THAT OUR SYSTEMS OF CARE REMAIN FLEXIBLE
AND RESPONSIVE TO THE CRISIS. I THINK THAT THIS CONVERSATION
IS AN IMPORTANT ONE THAT NEEDS TO BE HAD IN PUBLIC SETTING.
AS SUCH I AM CALLING FOR THE DEPARTMENT OF HOMELESSNESS
AND SUPPORTIVE HOUSING DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC HEALTH,
OFFICE OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES AND MAYOR'S BUDGET TO
REPORT AND I LOOK FORWARD TO A PRODUCTIVE CONVERSATION NEXT
YEAR. >> COLLEAGUE AND I ALSO HAVE TO
INTRODUCE A DRAFTING REQUEST FOR A CHARTER AMENDMENT TO
CREATE A SAN FRANCISCO MUNICIPAL FINANCIAL
CORPORATION'S AND PUBLIC BANK. THIS IS TRIED AND TESTED
STRATEGY THAT HAS ACHIEVED A TREMENDOUS IMPACT IN CITIES
ACROSS THE WORLD. >> CITY ATTORNEY DAVID CHIU
DURING HIS TEN YEARS IN THE STATE ASSEMBLY WAS THE LEAD
AUTHOR OF THE CALIFORNIA PUBLIC BANKING ACT WHICH WAS PASSED BY
THE CALIFORNIA LEGISLATURE AND SIGNED BY GOVERNOR NEWSOM
IN 2020. OUTPOUR OF SUPERVISORS HAS
ALREADY TAKEN SUBSTANTIVE STEPS TO MAKE THIS CHARTER AMENDMENT
POSSIBLE. >> IN 2021 THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS ESTABLISHED IT THE SAN FRANCISCO REINVESTMENT
WORKING GROUP TO OVERSEE THE FORMATION OF A BUSINESS
AND GOVERNMENT AND GOVERNANCE PLAN CONSISTING OF THE
COMPTROLLER TREASURER TECHNICAL EXPERTISE IN FINANCIAL
INSTITUTIONS, AFFORDABLE HOUSING FINANCING, SMALL
BUSINESS LENDING, ENVIRONMENTAL JUSTICE AND RENEWABLE ENERGY.
IN 2023 THE REINVESTMENT WORKING GROUP PREPARED IT A
FINAL GOVERNANCE PLAN BUSINESS PLAN AND AND VIABILITY STUDY
FOR SAN FRANCISCO MUNICIPAL FINANCIAL CORPORATIONS AND A
SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC BANK WHICH WAS THEN ACCEPTED BY THE BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS. THIS CHARTER AMENDMENT TAKES
DOE'S PLANS THAT WERE ACCEPTED BY THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
AND CODIFIED THE MISSION AND STRUCTURE FOR THE MUNICIPAL
FINANCIAL CORPORATION AND PUBLIC BANK IN OUR CITY
CHARTER. >> IT ESTABLISHES A GOOD
GOVERNANCE STRUCTURE AS ALLOWED IN THE FINANCIAL GOVERNANCE
PLAN UNANIMOUSLY ACCEPTED BY THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WHICH
ESTABLISHES SIGNIFICANT SAFEGUARDS OVERSIGHTS CHECK
AND BALANCES AND ACCOUNTABILITY TO PROTECT THE PUBLIC INTEREST
. >> THIS PLAN ENSURES THAT THE
PUBLIC BANK WILL BE RUN BY SECURITY BANKING PROFESSIONALS
BANKERS APPOINTED BY THE TREASURER, COMPTROLLER, CITY
ATTORNEY, MAYOR AND BOARD SUPERVISORS.
>> WE HAVE BEEN GRAPPLING TO EVENTS AND FINANCE LARGE SCALE
SOLUTION THAT CAN ADDRESS OUR HOUSING AFFORDABILITY
CHALLENGES THAT CAN ASSIST SMALL BUSINESS TO SURVIVE
AND THRIVE AND CAN FINANCE THE INVESTMENTS NEEDED TO ACHIEVE
CLIMATE SUSTAINABILITY. THESE ARE THREE OF OUR CITY'S
CRITICAL PRIORITIES AND MOST CONSISTENT AND PERSISTENT
CHALLENGES. >> AT ITS HEART THE MUNICIPAL
FINANCIAL CORPORATION AND PUBLIC BANK WILL ALLOW SAN
FRANCISCO TO INVEST APOPHIS INTO SAN FRANCISCO.
IT WILL ALLOW SAN FRANCISCO TO DEVELOP FINANCING TOOLS
AND LENDING PARTIES THAT WILL BENEFIT SAN FRANCISCO.
SAN FRANCISCO VOTERS AGREE. >> A RECENT CITYWIDE POLL
CONDUCTED BY THE UNDERPIN AND SWAY BUBBLES SHOW THAT 67%
OF LIKELY SAN FRANCISCO VOTERS SUPPORT THE CREATION OF A
PUBLIC BANK. THIS INCREASES TO 16 9%.
>> ITS FIRST INVESTMENTS ARE RENEWABLE ENERGY WITH FUTURE
INVESTMENT IN AFFORDABLE HOUSING AND OTHER CRITICAL
PUBLIC PROJECTS. WE DON'T HAVE TO GUESS IF THIS
WORKS. THE BANK OF NORTH DAKOTA HAS
BEEN SUCCESSFULLY OPERATING SINCE 1919.
>> IT HAS CONSISTENTLY DELIVERED PROFITS BACK TO THE
STATE SUPPORTING ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT AND KEEPING THE
LOCAL ECONOMY STABLE EVEN DURING THE 2008 FINANCIAL
CRISIS AND COVID PANDEMIC. >> THE CITIES FROM LOS ANGELES
TO NEW YORK CITY ARE ALSO ADVANCING PUBLIC BANK
STRATEGIES. I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE
CRITICAL LEADERSHIP THAT SUPERVISOR FIELDER HAS PLAYED
AS WELL AS SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC BANK COALITION TO EDUCATE
AND ELEVATE PUBLIC BANKS STRATEGIES.
COLLEAGUES, I LOOK FORWARD TO YOUR SUPPORT AND THE REST OF
SUMMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHEN SUPERVISOR DORSEY SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD.
>> COLLEAGUES TODAY I'M INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION OF
SUPPORT FOR ASSEMBLY BILL 1836 AUTHORED BY SEVEN MEMBERS JESSE
GABRIEL AND CHRIS WARD. FOR THE LAST SEVERAL YEARS THE
CALIFORNIA STATE NONPROFIT SECURITY GRANT PROGRAM HAS
PROVIDED TENS OF MILLIONS OF DOLLARS A YEAR TO NONPROFIT
ORGANIZATIONS WHO ARE AT HIGH RISK OF VIOLENT ATTACKS DUE TO
IDEOLOGY, BELIEFS OR MISSION. >> OUR MOST VULNERABLE
COMMUNITY SPACES HAVE BENEFITED FROM THE FUNDING PROTECTING KEY
ASSETS SUCH AS CONGREGATION BETH SHALOM, THE GLIDE
FOUNDATION AND THE ISLAMIC CENTER OF SAN FRANCISCO.
HOWEVER, SAN FRANCISCO'S ETHNIC CULTURAL AND LGBTQ PLUS GROUPS
DON'T SPEND ALL OF THEIR TIME INDOORS.
WE'RE A CITY OF STREET FAIRS, PARADES AND PARK ACTIVATIONS
THAT TAKE ADVANTAGE OF OUR PUBLIC SPACES TO CELEBRATE OUR
INCREDIBLE DIVERSITY. BUT UNDER CURRENT LAW SECURITY
FOR EVENTS OUTSIDE OF PERMANENT NONPROFIT FACILITIES ARE NOT
ELIGIBLE FOR THIS GRANT PROGRAM.
>> AB 1836 CHOW CHANGES THAT. IT ALLOWS FOR CULTURAL EVENTS
RUN BY NONPROFITS TO APPLY FOR AND RECEIVE FUNDS TO HELP KEEP
CELEBRANTS SAFE FROM POLITICAL POTENTIAL HATE MOTIVATED
VIOLENCE. >> HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS OF SAN
FRANCISCANS AND VISITORS MAY STAND TO BENEFIT FROM THIS
LEGISLATION AS OUR EVENTS ARE MADE SAFER AND OUR LOCAL
NONPROFITS MANY OF WHICH ARE LIVING AT A RAZOR'S EDGE
FINANCIALLY WON'T HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT SECURITY BILLS BREAKING
THE BANK. EVEN AS HATE CRIMES REMAIN AN
EVER PRESENT THREAT TO MARGINALIZED COMMUNITIES, AB 18
36 HAS A LONG LIST OF LOCAL SUPPORTERS INCLUDED INCLUDING
THE JEWISH FEDERATION BAY AREA L.A PARA TRANS LATINAS NEON
MUNCHIE STREET FAIR AND PFLAG AG.
SAN FRANCISCO THANK YOU TO OUR FLAG.
THANK YOU TO DR. EMILY ROSSI FROM THE JAPANTOWN AND TASK
FORCE FOR BRINGING THIS LEGISLATION TO MY ATTENTION.
AND I ASK COLLEAGUES FOR YOUR SUPPORT OF THIS RESOLUTION
AND THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MOHAMAD SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN THANK YOU, MADAM
CLERK. COLLEAGUES, I AM ASKING THAT WE
ADJOURN TO TODAY'S MEETING IN HONOR OF HELENE WENZEL WHO
DIED AT HER HOME ON FEBRUARY 4TH, 2026.
SHE WAS 82 YEARS OLD. ILENE WAS A PIONEERING SAN
FRANCISCO ATTORNEY, EDUCATOR AND ADVOCATE FOR THE
COMMUNITY. HER LIFE WAS DEFINED BY HER
EXTRAORDINARY INTELLECT AND UNSHAKABLE COMMITMENT TO
SOCIAL JUSTICE. >> AFTER EARNING A PH.D.
IN FRENCH LITERATURE FROM UC BERKELEY, SHE BEGAN HER
PROFESSIONAL LIFE IN ACADEMIA SERVING AS A PROFESSOR OF
FRENCH AND WOMEN'S STUDIES AT YALE UNIVERSITY AND LATER AT
SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY. >> HER DESIRE TO PROVIDE DIRECT
COMPASSIONATE ADVOCACY FOR HER COMMUNITY TOOK HER FROM THE
CLASSROOM TO THE PRACTICE OF LAW.
SHE EARNED A DEGREE FROM NEW COLLEGE SCHOOL OF LAW
AND OPENED THE LAW OFFICES OF EILEEN V WENZEL WHERE SHE
PRACTICED FOR NEARLY 30 YEARS IN THE AREAS OF ELDER LAW,
PROBATE AND ESTATE PLANNING. SHE BECAME A VITAL RESOURCE FOR
LGBTQ PLUS INDIVIDUALS AND SENIORS NAVIGATING COMPLEX
LEGAL LANDSCAPES WITH BOTH RIGOR AND EMPATHY.
HER LEADERSHIP IN THE FIELD IS RECOGNIZED BY PEERS WHO ELECTED
HER PRESIDENT OF THE NORTHERN CALIFORNIA CHAPTER OF THE
NATIONAL ACADEMY OF ELDER LAW ATTORNEYS.
BEYOND HER LAW PRACTICE, EILEEN WAS A LONG TERM SUPPORTER OF
THE NATIONAL CENTER FOR LESBIAN RIGHTS, AN ACTIVE MEMBER OF BAY
AREA LAWYERS FOR INDIVIDUAL FREEDOM AND A GENEROUS DONOR TO
ORGANIZATIONS FOCUSED ON EMPOWERING WOMEN AND PROTECTING
CIVIL LIBERTIES. SHE WAS KNOWN FOR HER SHARP
WIT, SCHOLARLY MIND AND DEEP CAPACITY FOR FRIENDSHIP.
SHE'S SURVIVED BY ABBY ZINBERG, HER WIFE AND PARTNER OF 37
YEARS AS WELL AS A VAST NETWORK OF FRIENDS AND FANS.
COUNT ME AMONG THEM. I WILL VERY MUCH MISS RUNNING
INTO EILEEN AND ABBY OUT AND ABOUT ON 24TH STREET
AND NOVI VALLEY. REST IN PEACE AND POWER, EILEEN
WENZEL. MAY YOUR MEMORY BE A BLESSING.
>> THE REST I SUBMIT. THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
AND SEEING NO NAMES ON THE ROSTER THAT CONCLUDES THE
INTRODUCTION OF NEW BUSINESS. >> LET'S GO TO PUBLIC COMMENT.
>> THOSE OF YOU WHO ARE HERE IN THE BOARD'S CHAMBER PLEASE
LINE UP ON YOUR RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER.
YOU ARE ABLE TO SPEAK TO THE MAYORAL APPEARANCE THE MINUTES
AS PRESENTED ITEMS 36 THROUGH 44.
THOSE ARE THE ITEMS ON THE ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE
REFERENCE CALENDAR AND OTHER GENERAL MATTERS NOT ON THE
PUBLISHED AGENDA. AND WE ARE SETTING THE TIMER
FOR TWO MINUTES. >> LET'S HEAR FROM OUR FIRST
SPEAKER. WELCOME.
>> HI. YOU ACTUALLY DON'T HAVE TO PAY
ATTENTION TO THIS. THIS IS JUST ME ENTERTAINING
MYSELF BECAUSE YOU KNOW IN FASCIST TIMES IT'S LIKE
REALLY DEPRESSING AND . COMING HERE IS VERY DEPRESSING
WATCHING YOU DO WHAT YOU DO. >> SO I AM CURRENTLY READING
THE SOCIETY OF THE SPECTACLE BY GUIDE BOARD.
>> EVERYONE SHOULD BE READING AND THINKING MORE AND THINKING
CRITICALLY BECAUSE THE BILLIONAIRES DON'T WANT US TO
DO THAT. >> SO WHEN I READ I LIKE TO
THINK OF HOW THAT APPLIES TO MY LIFE AND WHAT I DO AND WHAT I
SEE. >> SO HERE ARE SOME FUN QUOTES.
THE SPECTACLE IS ABLE TO SUBJECT HUMAN BEINGS TO ITSELF
BECAUSE THE ECONOMY HAS ALREADY SUBJUGATED THEM AND IS NOTHING
OTHER THAN THE ECONOMY DEVELOPING FOR ITSELF.
>> IT IS AT ONCE A FAITHFUL REFLECTION OF THE PRODUCTION OF
THINGS AND A DISTORTING OBJECTIFICATION OF THE
PRODUCERS. >> YEAH WE ARE SO EDUCATED BY
THE ECONOMY WHICH RELATES TO THE MAYOR THIS EARLIER THIS
MEETING TALKING ABOUT ALL HOW HE HAS TO HURT US AGAINST HIS
WILL. HE DOESN'T WANT TO MAKE THESE
HARD BUDGET DECISIONS. >> BUT YOU KNOW THE ECONOMY
NOTHING HE CAN DO ABOUT THAT. >> WHAT ELSE?
>> OH, THE RAINING ECONOMIC SYSTEM IS A VICIOUS CIRCLE OF
ISOLATION AS TECHNOLOGIES ARE BASED ON ISOLATION AND THEY
CONTRIBUTE TO THAT SAME ISOLATION.
I THINK A LOT ABOUT SOCIAL MEDIA WITH THIS TOO.
>> FROM AUTOMOBILES TO TELEVISED AND THE GOODS THAT
THE SPECTACULAR SYSTEM CHOOSES TO PRODUCE ALSO SERVES AS ITS
WEAPONS FOR CONSTANTLY REINFORCING THE CONDITIONS THAT
ENGENDER LONELY CROWDS. I MEAN SOCIAL MEDIA IS A BIG
WEAPON BEING USED AGAINST PEOPLE TOO RIGHT NOW AND DANIEL
LURIE AND HIS INSTAGRAM REELS AND EVERYTHING'S GREAT.
>> WE'RE BOUNCING BACK. LET'S IGNORE HOMELESS PEOPLE.
LET'S IGNORE ALL THE THAT'S HAPPENING ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
>> ICE IS GREAT. HE IMPLIES HE DOESN'T REALLY
SAY ANYTHING BAD ABOUT ICE. >> I GUESS THAT'S ALL I HAVE
TIME FOR. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU LIAM MCKEEVER FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER .
THANK YOU MEMBERS OF THE BOARD. MY NAME IS JIM MCCARTHY ON
FEBRUARY SECOND, 2026 I RECEIVED PRINTED INFORMATION
CONCERNING THE INSPECTOR GENERAL'S OFFICE OF SAN
FRANCISCO THAT REVEALED THE COMPTROLLER'S OFFICE WAS IN THE
PROCESS OF DEVELOPING POLICIES AND PROCEDURES FOR ITS
OPERATION AND ABOUT THE IG'S AUTHORITY AND DUTIES.
AS FAR AS I KNOW THERE IS NO UPDATE AS OF YET.
>> I HUMBLY REQUEST THAT THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD SUPERVISORS
ENCOURAGE THE COMPTROLLER'S OFFICE TO COMPLETE IT AND MAKE
IT PUBLIC. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS VIRGINIA TAYLOR.
I'M HERE FROM SAFE AND SOUND IN THE FAMILY SERVICES ALLIANCE
AND I JUST WANT TO THANK EVERYONE ON THE BOARD FOR THE
RESOLUTION THAT'S BEING INTRODUCED AND FOR BEING AT THE
PRESS CONFERENCE AT LUNCH AND HONOR OF CHILD ABUSE
PREVENTION AWARENESS MONTH. >> WE REALLY APPRECIATE ALL
YOUR SUPPORT AND EVERYONE STANDING TOGETHER.
YOU KNOW, SHOWS THAT PARENTS WORKING AND EVERYONE WORKING
TOGETHER HELPS PARENTS REDUCE STRESS AND BUILD RESILIENCE
AND STRENGTHEN THE CONNECTIONS THAT HELP CHILDREN GROW SAFE
AND SUPPORTED. SO TOGETHER WE'RE BUILDING A
STRONGER COMMUNITY WHERE EVERYONE CAN THRIVE AND WE
REALLY APPRECIATE ALL OF YOU AND THAT SUPPORT.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU, VIRGINIA TAYLOR FOR
YOUR COMMENTS. >> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER
. GOOD AFTERNOON.
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS PRESIDENT MAILMAN AND THE GENERAL BOARD.
>> I JUST CAN'T BELIEVE WHAT YOU PEOPLE PERPETRATED LAST
WEEK. IT'S LIKE BRINGING WASHINGTON
DC POLITICS TO SAN FRANCISCO THAT WAS PURELY PERFORMATIVE
TAKING I GUESS FROM THE PLANNING COMMISSION STRUCTURING
THAT THREE THREE TIE SO THE BOARD COMES OUT WITH A55 TIE.
>> I NOTICE THAT DISTRICT NINE SEAT IS STILL EMPTY
AND APPARENTLY I HAD TO READ IN THE PAPER BECAUSE PEOPLE
WERE MUMBLING LAST WEEK ABOUT WHAT WAS ACTUALLY HAPPENING
ABOUT THAT DISTRICT NINE WELL APPARENTLY WHEN I READ IN THE
PAPER SHE HAS A LEAVE OF ABSENCE FOR 30 DAYS WHICH IS
AFTER THE ELECTION AND SHE IS A PRODUCT OF A OF A SEVERAL
SUPERVISORS FROM CAMPUS TO MOVE TO RONAN AND TO FEEL THERE
AND THERE ARE OCCUPYING A VERY CRITICAL UP SUPERVISOR DISTRICT
. >> THE MISSION DISTRICT IS SO
IMPORTANT AND IT'S RIGHT NOW RUNNING LAWLESS.
THERE IS NO REAL DIRECTION YOU SHOULD PRESSURE PRESSURE THIS
SUPERVISOR TO EITHER AS THEY SAY IN THE ARMY DEFECATE OR GET
OFF THE TOILET. >> SHE'S GOT TO DO SOMETHING AT
SOME TIME. YOU CAN'T LET THIS THIS GROUP
AND YOU CAN'T ACT LIKE A CABAL AND PROTECT THIS PERSON.
I LOVE WHAT SHE WAS DOING. I OFTEN SUPPORTED THE BANK OF
SAN FRANCISCO IS A BRILLIANT IDEA.
I SUPPORTED THAT I SUPPORTER AND AGAINST MAYOR LURIE AND I
WISH YOU WERE BACK BUT SHE'S GOT TO COME BACK OR NO.
>> ALL RIGHT. ARE THERE ANY OTHER SPEAKERS
WHO WOULD LIKE TO ADDRESS THE BOARD DURING GENERAL PUBLIC
COMMENT, MR. PRESIDENT? >> ALL RIGHT.
>> PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED.
MADAM CLERK. LET'S GO TO OUR FOR ADOPTION
WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA PLEASE CALL ITEMS 36
THROUGH 44 ITEMS 36 THROUGH 44 WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION
WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED FOR
ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST READING ANY MEMBER MAY
REQUIRE A RESOLUTION ON FIRST READING TO GO TO COMMITTEE
SUPERVISED DORSEY CAN WE PULL ITEM 36?
YES SUPERVISOR SAUTER 739 PLEASE.
>> OKAY. SUPERVISOR WALTON I'D LIKE TO
SEE AN ITEM 37 TO COMMITTEE RIGHT.
I DON'T SEE ANYBODY ELSE SO MADAM CLERK CAN YOU CALL THE
ROLL ON THE REMAINING BALANCE OF THE ITEMS?
>> THAT'S ITEMS 36 THROUGH 44 BUT EXCLUDING 3637 AND 39.
YES WE HAVE HERE 38, 4041, 4243 AND 44 SUPERVISOR MELGAR I
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUTER SAUTER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL
CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES SUPERVISOR WONG
WONG EYES SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD BACHMANN I
AND SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN I RANDLEMAN I THERE ARE TEN EYES
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED
AND MOTION IS APPROVED. >> MOTIONS ARE APPROVED MADAM
CLERK CAN YOU PLEASE CALL ITEM 36 ITEM 36 RESOLUTION TO
DESIGNATE APRIL 19TH THROUGH APRIL 25TH 2026 AS NATIONAL
CRIME VICTIMS RIGHTS WEEK IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO. >> SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU
PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN COLLEAGUES TODAY I ENCOURAGE YOU TO JOIN
ME IN RECOGNIZING NATIONAL CRIME VICTIMS RIGHTS WEEK HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO WHICH WILL BE OBSERVED THIS YEAR FROM APRIL
19TH THROUGH APRIL 25TH. >> THIS WEEK IS ABOUT ENSURING
THAT IN ALL OUR DISCUSSIONS ON PUBLIC SAFETY WE NEVER LOSE
SIGHT OF THOSE WHO HAVE BEEN HARMED BY CRIME.
BEHIND EVERY CRIME STATISTIC IS A CRIME VICTIM A PERSON, A
FAMILY, A COMMUNITY IMPACTED AND TOO OFTEN THOSE VOICES GET
LOST. >> THIS YEAR'S THEME LISTEN ACT
ADVOCATE PROTECT VICTIMS SERVE COMMUNITIES IS EXACTLY THE CALL
TO ACTION WE NEED SUPPORTING THE RIGHTS OF VICTIMS ISN'T
PASSIVE. IT REQUIRES US TO LISTEN YES,
BUT ALSO TO ACT TO SUSTAIN INVESTMENTS AND SERVICES AND TO
ENSURE COORDINATION AMONG MULTIPLE AGENCIES TO ENSURE
THAT OUR JUSTICE SYSTEM IS RESPONSIBLE AND ACCESSIBLE
AND ROOTED IN DIGNITY. IN SAN FRANCISCO WE'VE MADE
COMMENDABLE PROGRESS INCLUDING THE CREATION OF THE OFFICE OF
VICTIMS AND WITNESS RIGHTS. BUT WE ALSO KNOW THERE'S MORE
WORK TO DO ESPECIALLY FOR COMMUNITIES THAT
DISPROPORTIONATELY FACE BARRIERS TO ACCESSING JUSTICE
OR OBTAINING NEEDED SUPPORT. I'M PROUD THAT OUR CITY HAS
LONG CENTERED VICTIMS AND SURVIVORS IN OUR PUBLIC
SAFETY EFFORTS. SIX MONTHS AGO YOU MAY RECALL
THAT I EULOGIZED FORMER DISTRICT ATTORNEY ARLO SMITH
IN THIS CHAMBER RECOGNIZING HIM FOR AMONG OTHER ACCOMPLISHMENTS
CREATING CALIFORNIA'S FIRST VICTIM SERVICES UNIT IN A
DISTRICT ATTORNEY'S OFFICE AS FAR BACK AS THE 1980S.
THAT OFFICE AND OTHER PROGRAMS LIKE IT HAVE BEEN INSTRUMENTAL
TO ENSURE THAT THOSE HARMED BY CRIME IN SAN FRANCISCO HAVE
PATHWAYS TO HEALING AND JUSTICE AND THAT COMMITMENT WAS
UNDERSCORED EVEN TODAY WITH THE RESOLUTION INTRODUCED BY
SUPERVISORS CHERYL AND MELGAR ON SEXUAL ASSAULT RESPONSE
AND PREVENTION. THANK YOU FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP
ON THAT. ON APRIL 20TH NEXT MONDAY
EVENING I'LL BE JOINING THE S.F. PD VICTIMS WALK ALONGSIDE
SURVIVORS AND ADVOCATES. I WANT TO THANK CHIEF DERRICK
LIU AND OUR CURRENT DISTRICT ATTORNEY BROOK JENKINS FOR
THEIR LEADERSHIP IN BRINGING COMMUNITIES TOGETHER TOGETHER
AROUND THAT. AND I ENCOURAGE COLLEAGUES TO
JOIN US AT THE END OF THE DAY. A SAFER CITY ISN'T SOLELY ONE
THAT REDUCES CRIME RATES. IT'S ONE THAT STANDS WITH
VICTIMS CONSISTENTLY AND WITHOUT EXCEPTION.
SAN FRANCISCO CAN BE PROUD OF ITS LONG HISTORY OF DOING THAT.
IT'S A CIVIC CREED WORTH HONORING AND RECOMMITTING TO AS
WE OBSERVE NATIONAL CRIME VICTIMS RIGHTS WEEK THIS YEAR.
I HOPE YOU'LL SUPPORT IT. SUPERVISOR WONG LIKE TO REQUEST
TO ADD MY NAME AS CO-SPONSOR NOTED GUZMAN I BELIEVE
COLLEAGUES WE CAN TAKE THAT ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 39.
>> ITEM 39 RESOLUTION TO SUPPORT HOUSE RESOLUTION NUMBER
2410 THE REVITALIZING DOWNTOWNS AND MAIN STREETS ACT AUTHORED
BY UNITED STATES REPRESENTATIVES MIKE CASEY
AND JAIME GOMEZ WHICH WILL BE WHICH WILL PROVIDE A FEDERAL
TAX CREDIT TO FACILITATE THE CON THE CONVERSION OF OFFICE
AND OTHER COMMERCIAL BUILDINGS INTO HOUSING.
>> SUPERVISOR SAUDER THANK YOU PRESIDENT GENTLEMAN I JUST NEED
TO MAKE A SMALL CLERICAL CHANGE ON HERE TO REFERENCE THE
CORRECT INDIVIDUAL BEING U.S. REPRESENTATIVE MIKE CAREY
AND U.S. REPRESENTATIVE MIKE CASEY.
SO THOSE THAT SIMPLE AMENDMENT HAS BEEN CIRCULATED TO EVERYONE
AND I WOULD ASK TO MOVE TO AMEND ITEM 39 ACCORDINGLY
SUPERVISOR SAUTER HAS MADE A MOTION IS THERE A SECOND
SECONDED BY CHEN? COLLEAGUES I THINK WE CAN CHECK
THAT MOTION WITHOUT OBJECTION. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
AMENDMENT IS AS PASSED AND THEN I THINK WE CAN TAKE THE AMENDED
. >> MADAM CLERK IS LIKE NODDING
YOU CAN GET IT OUT. YOU CAN GET IT OUT OF OUT OF
IT. WE CAN TAKE THE AMENDED ITEM.
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE AMENDED
RESOLUTION IS IS ADOPTED AS APPROVED.
>> OKAY. >> AND WITH THAT MADAM CLERK UH
,DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS?
>> I HAVE NO TO REPORT, MR. PRESIDENT.
ALL RIGHT. COULD YOU PLEASE READ THE
IN MEMORIAM? >> TODAY'S MEETING WILL BE
ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUAL ON
BEHALF OF PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN FOR THE LATE DR. HELEN WENZEL.
>> AND I THINK THAT BRINGS US TO THE END OF OUR AGENDA, MADAM
CLERK. DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS
BEFORE US TODAY? >> THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS
FOR TODAY. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK WE ARE
ADJOURNED